THE JOURNEY BEGINS...
旅程开始了...
I'm such an idiot.
我真是个白痴。
I always do this.
我总是这么做。
Why did I take the 58?
我为什么要走58号公路?
I'm gonna be late.
我要迟到了。
I'm so tired of being late.
我厌倦了迟到。
Maybe I should get off?
也许我该下高速了？
Of course, everyone's gonna let me get over, are you?
当然，每个人都会让我过去的，是吗？
No, of course not.
不，这怎么可能！
At least acquiescing to everyone I should just...
至少每个人应该默许我...
get in...
插队进去...
just do that all the time at doing about everything.
做任何事情都要这样。
And then I end up late.
我要迟到了。
You look like the walking dead.
我看起来就像行尸走肉。
Looks a pale, this can't be how I'm supposed to look.
脸色苍白，这不是我应该看起来的样子。
Just behind my eyes so tired and so tired.
苍茫双眼之后的我，是如此的疲惫。
I should go somewhere.
我应该去散散心。
I should take a vacation.
我应该去度个假。
Oh, my god, it's him.
哦，天啊，是他。
Please don't see me, I look awful.
千万别看我，我看起来太糟糕了。
Please don't look over here.
千万别往这边看。
What am I doing？
我这是在做什么呀？
It doesn't matter if he sees me.
他看不看得见我有啥关系。
I'm not in his league, that's for sure.
我和他不是一个级别，这是肯定的。
Why do I have to carry out  weight in my stomach?
为什么我要吃这么多东西？
Looks like a Buddha,
看起来像一尊佛，
but not as bright.
但却没那么聪明。
I need to stop drinking red wine and eating cheese.
我要停止喝红酒和吃奶酪了。
Cancer, I just know.
会得癌症的，我知道这一点。
It's my family, my dad, uncle.
我的家庭、父亲还有叔叔，他们都得了。
I eat like a pig.
我吃得像头猪。
He gets to know how scared I am.
他会知道我有多害怕。
It's like unholy by myself I don't know where to go.
这就像我自己的不圣洁，我不知道该去哪里。
This isn't me much, today just water.
这根本不是我，今天我只喝水。
I have David Brooke to looks again
我让大卫 · 布鲁克再看看。
All right.
好吧。
I'm not eating donuts, I'm not eating.
我不吃甜甜圈，不再吃了。
I love donuts.
不过我喜欢甜甜圈。
I feel wonderful this morning.
今天早上我感觉好极了。
I love living in the city.
我喜欢住在这个城市。
And Scott, I'm so excited to spend this weekend with him.
我很高兴能和斯考特共度这个周末。
Look at you, happy people are so annoying.
看看你，快乐的人真烦人。
Hello.
你好。
Hey, Scott, I was just thinking about you.
嘿，斯科特，我正想着你呢。
Hey, you drop this.
嘿，你落下东西了。
I'm willing to change.
我愿意改变。
I'm willing to release my old patterns and negative beliefs.
我愿意释放我的旧模式和消极信念。
The power that created me has given me the power
那个创造我的力量给了我
to create my new life.
创造新生活的力量。
I choose positive fulfilling new thoughts.
我选择积极充实的新思想。
Beginning new, right here, right now!
新的开始，就在这里，就在此刻!
All of us are on a journey whether we know it or not.
不管我们知道与否，我们所有人都在旅途中。
We are all on a journey of learning to express
我们都在学习如何在这个世界上
our full potential in this world.
充分展示我们的潜力的过程中。
Most of us have learned to view our thoughts as
我们大多数人都学会了把我们的想法
a reflection of the outside world,
看作是外部世界的反映，
a reflection of what is happening to us.
是发生在我们身上的事情的反映。
But what if that's not how the universe works,
但是，如果宇宙不是这样运作，
what if with every thought you think
如果你的每一个想法
you are actually creating your present and your future,
实际上都在创造你的现在和你的未来，
what if you are creating the story of your life
如果你正在用此刻的想法
with the very thought you are thinking now.
创造你的人生故事，那会怎么样呢？
Then perhaps if we are willing
那么也许，如果我们愿意
to change the way we think,
改变我们的思维方式，
wondrous new possibilities would
奇妙的新的可能性
begin to reveal themselves to us.
将开始向我们展现。
And our lives would move in a whole new direction.
而且我们的生活会朝着一个全新的方向发展。
It all starts with taking the first step.
所有这一切都从迈出第一步开始。
生命的重建
Every thought we think and every word we speak
我们的每一个想法和每一句话
is creating our future.
都在创造着我们的未来。
It's as though our thoughts go out into the universe and
这就好像我们的思想进入了宇宙，
are accepted and brought back to us as experience.
被其接受并作为经验带回给我们去体验。
You become what you think about,
不管你愿不愿意，
whether you want it or not.
你都会成为你所想的。
The thought that you are thinking is vibration in nature
你所想的念头在本质上是振动的，
and therefore attractive in nature.
因此在本质上是有吸引力的。
So when you care enough to take the time to change it
所以当你足够关注，
from what you are terming negative to positive,
花时间把念头从消极变为积极时，
you have shifted your point of attraction.
你已经改变了你的吸引点。
Nothing is more important than understanding than that.
没有什么比理解这个观念更重要的了。
If you just did that one simple thing
如果你只是做了件简单的事情，
of spotting the limitations and
即发现你思维中的
the limitations in your thinking and
限制和局限性，
trading those in for a positive new thought in that area,
并将这些换成该领域的积极的新想法，
it'll eventually lead you to all the other stuff,
它最终会引导你去做其他所有的事情，
it'll lead you through.
它会指引你去经历这些事情。
And how would our lives be different
如果我们能穿过所有的静止状态，
if we can cut through all of the static
在我们的生活中简单地选择
and simply choose in our lives
我们希望每天的每一时刻
what we would like each moment of each day
或我们的关系或我们的富足
or our relationships or our abundance or our careers
或我们的事业或和平和我们的家庭的样子，
or the peace and our families to look like.
我们的生活会有什么不同。
What would our lives look like if we could do that.
如果我们能做到这一点，我们的生活会是什么样子。
We're so busy on the cell phone,
我们忙着打电话，
we'r texting messaging somebody,
我们忙着给他人发短信，
we're on the computer,
我们忙着用电脑，
we're on the internet ,
我们沉迷于上网，
we're watching soap operas,
我们浸淫于看肥皂剧，
once again we're looking outside of us.
我们不断把目光投向我们之外。
People don't realize their greatest potential
人们没有意识到他们最大的潜力，
because they think it's from an outside source.
因为他们认为它来自于外部。
When it's so divinely ordained within them.
而它是如此神圣地安居在我们心里。
Now it's how do you turn that around.
现在的问题是如何扭转这种局面。
It starts with thinking differently.
这要从改变知见开始。
You can be fully supported by the universe by following
你可以通过追随你的梦想、你的激情和
your dreams and your passions and your inner guidance.
你的内在引导，得到宇宙的全力支持。
You're willingness to contemplate yourself as a person
你愿意将自己视为一个
who is capable of attracting into your life what you want,
能够吸引你想要的东西的人，
having the kind of relationships that you want,
拥有你想要的那种关系，
being able to have abundance
能够在匮乏之地
where scarcity always exists.
拥有丰盛富足。
All you have to do is begin the process
你所要做的就是愿意考虑
by being willing to contemplate
丰盛富足其实就在你的生活中
the presence of that in your life.
来开始这个过程。
I started to be introduced to
在生命的某个阶段，我开始被告知
looking at the world in a different way.
要以不同的方式看世界。
For example,
比如说,
through Louise's book, 'You can heal your life',
通过路易丝的书《生命的重建》，
which was very influential to me early on.
这本书在早期对我影响很大。
When I thought, wow, there's something
当时我想，哇，
about the way I think that may be influencing
我的一些思维方式可能正在影响
what's happening in my life.
我生活中所发生的事情。
We now know that
我们现在知道，
we can rewire our patterns in our brain
我们可以通过认知行为疗法或肯定句
with cognitive behavior therapy or affirmations.
来重新构建我们大脑中的模式。
It changes the way our brains are wired
这些方法改变了我们大脑（神经元）的连接方式，
and they light up differently.
它们以不同的方式连接起来并发挥作用。
So it's not just this fluff, woo woo, stuff with purple,
它不是那种花里胡哨、胡言乱语的东西，
but it really has biochemical, neurochemical,
而是确实具有生化、神经化学、
neuropharmacological effects, just as effective,
神经药理学的效用，
if not more effective than Prozac, Zoloft,
与百忧解、左洛复等其它
whatever else you have.
你拥有的药物一样有效。
So Louise Hay, former model, former therapist,
露易丝 · 海之前做过模特和治疗师,
discovers something by observation
通过观察有了一些发现，
that science supports decades later.
这些发现几十年后得到了科学的支持。
There's not one person here
这里没有一个人
that cannot improve the quality of their life.
不能改善他们的生活品质。
I constantly do it.
我经常这样做。
What I really ask for is
我真正想要的是
how can I increase my understanding.
如何提高我的领悟力。
Because the more I understand about
因为我越是了解生活
how life works and how thought works,
和思想是如何运作的，
the better my life gets.
我的生活就越美好。
I have just entered my eighties day and
我刚进入八十多岁的高龄，
wonderful wonderful things are unfolding before me,
精彩的事情正在我面前展开,
it's extraordinary.
太不可思议了。
And I have made a decision that this decade is
而且我已经做出了决定，
going to be the best decade of my life.
往后十年将是我生命中最好的十年。
My life as far as I know
据我所知，
was very good until I was 18 months old
在我18个月大之前，我的生活非常好，
and then everything hit the fan.
之后一切都发生了变化。
And my parents got divorced and
我的父母离婚了，
I was put out into a foster home.
我被送到一个寄养家庭。
And then later I came back with my mother and
后来我回到我母亲身边，
then I was about 5 years old when she remarried.
在我大约5岁的时候，她再婚了。
And she remarried what turned out to be a brutalize,
想不到的是，她再婚的对象是个残忍之人,
we didn't know that at the time.
而我们当时并不知道。
So the next 10 years of my life
接下来的十年，
were very very challenging,
我的生活非常非常具有挑战性，
there was a lot of physical abuse and sexual abuse.
在这过程中我受到很多的身体虐待和性虐待。
I grew up in a family where really you were taught
在成长的家庭里，我被教导说，
that you were no good, you were worthless,
“你不好，你一无是处，
nobody loved you and nobody would love you.
没有人爱你，也不会有人爱你”。
And when you have that belief then
当你有了这种信念，
life gives you those experiences.
生活就会给你相应的体验。
I was raped by a neighbor at one point.
我曾经被一个邻居强奸过。
And the man got 16 years for it.
这个人因此被判了16年。
There was another neighbor that was after me.
还有一个邻居在追求我。
This was all when I was very little.
这一切都发生在我很小的时候。
And then about the time I became a teenager,
后来我长大成为青少年时，
my stepfather stopped beating me
继父不再打我，
and started to have sex with me.
开始和我做爱。
And that was much harder for me to take.
这让我很难接受。
So I left home at 15.
所以我15岁就离开了家。
I knew nothing,
那时我懵懂无知，
I had no social skills whatsoever.
一点社交技巧也没有。
But I was out of the house.
但我离家出走了。
I was starved for love and anybody who'd be nice to me,
我渴望爱，任何对我好的人，
I went to bed with.
我都会与之上床。
And so within a year I had a baby.
不到一年，我就有了一个孩子。
And I couldn't take care of the baby,
我照顾不好自己，
I couldn't take care of me.
更没法照顾孩子。
But I found the child a really good home,
但我给孩子找了个好人家，
a couple who wanted a baby very much
他们是一对非常想要孩子
and couldn't have one.
却没有孩子的夫妇。
And so I lived with them for the last two months
我在医院里用他们的名字登记住院，
and I had it in their name at the hospital.
并和他们在一起住了两个月。
And after five days I left.
五天后我离开了他们。
And what I did was I went back to my home.
我回到我原来的家。
I got my mother and I said,
我找到了妈妈，并对她说：
you do not have to take this any longer,
“你不用再忍受了,
you're getting out of here.
你要离开这里”。
And we both left.
后来我们都离开了。
And we were together for almost a year.
我们在一起近一年。
And then I said to myself, you know,
后来我对自己说，
she's okay, she's fine now, she's in good shape.
“她没事，她现在很好，身体很好”。
And I took off.
于是我就离开了她。
And I went to Chicago for
之后，我去了芝加哥三个星期，
three weeks and stayed five years.
并在那里呆了五年。
And then I went to New York
后来我又去了纽约三个星期，
for three weeks and I stayed 30 years.
之后在那里呆了30年。
And bumbled through life doing the best I could
用我所拥有的理解和知识，
with the understanding and knowledge that I had,
尽我所能在生活中蹒跚而行,
which was really nothing.
却一无所获。
I started out working in dime stores and things like that.
我开始在廉价商店之类的地方工作。
And then when I hit New York,
后来我到了纽约，
life sort of changed for me.
我的人生开始了变化。
And I became a model, a showroom model.
我成了一个模特，一个陈列室的模特。
And I'd had no education,
我没有受过教育，
so it was a very good job for me because
所以这对我来说是个很好的工作，
I couldn't be a secretary or anything like that.
因为我做不了秘书或者类似的工作。
And I did that for many years,
我做了模特很多年，
I married a upper-class englishman,
嫁给了一个上流社会的英国人，
which was a very nice experience.
这是一个非常美好的经历。
And I stopped modeling at that time.
从那时起，我就不再做模特了。
And we had 18 rather wonderful years together.
我们一起度过了18年的美好时光。
And I was learned a lot about life.
我学到了很多关于生活的东西。
And it was like my social training
这就像是我的社交训练，
because I had no social skills at all.
因为我根本没有社交技能。
And by the time we were parting I had learned a lot.
在我们分手的时候，我学到了很多东西。
But when the divorce came,
但当离婚来临之际，
it made me feel very much like so many women feel
像许多女人都有的感觉一样，这让我觉得自己
that I was a total failure.
是个彻头彻尾的失败者。
And I couldn't do it right,
我做得不好，
and everything was wrong again.
而一切又都错乱了。
And it was about five years later
大概五年后，
that I discovered this group
我发现了这个
called the "Church of Religious Science"
被称为“宗教科学教会”的团体，
which was where I heard
在那里我听到了这样的观念，
'if you change your thinking,
即，如果你改变你的想法，
you can change your life'.
你就能改变你的人生。
And that is where my life really began to change.
而这正是我的人生真正开始改变的地方。
We will have all these speakers,
这里所有的演讲者，
we're all going to say the same thing, really?
都会说同样的话，真的吗？
But we're going to do it in slightly different ways and
但是我们会用稍微不同的方式来讲，
we want everybody wants to hear things differently
我们希望每个人都听到不同的东西，
just because I say something some of you will get it,
只因我说了一些东西，你们中的一些人会明白，
some of you will say what is that woman talking about.
你们中的一些人会说，那个女人在说什么。
But so another teacher or 3 or 6 or 12
但是另一位老师，或者其他的老师们，
can say the same thing that I play in different words.
会用不同的方式来表达同样的事情。
And you go,
然后，你会说，
"Oh, it's brilliant, never heard that before".
“哦，太棒了，我以前从没听说过”。
WE ARE ALL ON A JOURNEY
我们都在旅途中
I was living like a lot of people do,
我就像很多人一样，
fairly unconsciously,
相当无意识地活着，
but not aware of my unconsciousness.
但是却没有觉察到自己的无意识。
You know just kind of going through life and
我只是在经历生活，
often feeling as though life was happening to me
并且经常感觉到好像生活发生在我身上，
that I was a victim to what was going on in my life.
我是我生活中发生的事情的受害者。
I was really like living in a comfortably numb place,
我真的像生活在一个舒适的麻木的地方，
you know there wasn't a depth of meaning in my life.
我的人生没有什么深层次的意义。
And I knew something was missing,
我知道我的人生少了点什么，
but I couldn't name it.
但却无法说出其是什么。
We had a tax business.
我们之前做税务生意。
I as it as a young girl
当我还是个小女孩时，
started apprenticing with my dad when I was 16.
在16岁时我就开始给我爸当学徒了。
He had a business in our home
开始时，我爸在家里做生意，
and we moved it out to a building.
后来我们搬到了一栋大楼里。
And in my early twenties,
在我二十岁出头的时候，
our business burnt to the ground.
我们家的生意全毁了。
One morning I got a phone call at 6:00am and
一天早上6点，我接到一个电话，
my mother called to say that the building was on fire.
我妈妈打电话来说我们的大楼着火了。
And when I got there there were
当我到达那里时，
firetrucks and police and news reporters.
来了消防车、警察和新闻记者。
And everything that meant anything
所有对我有意义的东西
to me was in that office.
都在那间办公室里。
And I had a nice front office with a glass front
我有一个漂亮的前台办公室，带玻璃门面的，
that I could look into.
我可以往里头看。
And now everything was burning.
而现在一切都付之一炬了。
When I was 12, I was brought to Boston,
我12岁的时候被带到波士顿做个手术，
to essentially have my spine completely fused.
以使我的脊柱完全融合。
And I remember looking up, saying,
我记得我抬起头，说，
I'm going to be a doctor in a scientist someday.
“我将来要成为一名科学家医生”。
And so I became prep med at the very early age.
我在很小的时候就成为了预科医生。
So after working as prep med,
在做了预科医生之后，
I started following a sleep lot,
我开始嗜睡，
up to 17h a day.
每天多达17小时。
They gave me a medicine and
他们给了我一种药，
the medicine started knocking out my bone marrow.
这种药物开始侵蚀我的骨髓。
And there wasn't another medicine that would help.
因为没有其他药物可以帮助我，
and so I was forced to look for other things.
所以我不得不寻找其它的东西。
I went to a bookstore in Boston.
我去了波士顿的一家书店。
And I look up at the shelf and there's this book
我抬头看到书架上有一本书，
called "You can heal your life" by Louise Hay.
叫做《生命的重建》 ，作者是路易斯 · 海。
And there were these things called affirmations
书中有个方法叫“自我肯定法”，
that if you did and you supposed to get,
如果你这样做了，你应该得到（疗愈），
you can heal your life was at the whole point.
其关键点是你可以疗愈你的生命。
I did reps just like you do in a gym
我做的动作就像你在健身房做的那样，
instead of lifting barbells or whatever you I lifted.
而不是去举杠铃或者其它之类的东西。
I love myself just the way I am,
“我爱自己如其所是”，
10 times.
这句话念10次。
And after three months I stopped falling asleep
三个月后，我不再沉睡了，
and I was able to go to medical school
我可以去上医学院了，
which was absolutely lovely.
那真是太好了。
I myself had terrible migraine headaches,
我有严重的偏头痛,
once a month, twice a month.
一个月犯一两次。
Whatever I'd been worked up in a Boston hospital
尽管我在波士顿医院
a week there with all kinds of testing,
做了一周的各种测试，
they never knew what it was.
但他们根本不知道病因是什么。
At the age of 19,
19岁的时候，
I had to do this English paper.
我不得不写篇英语论文。
And like most migrant personalities,
和大多数移民一样，
I needed to know what it was they wanted of me
我需要知道他们想从我这里得到什么，
and I couldn't figure it out.
而我根本弄不明白。
When I came out of the library,
当我从图书馆出来时，
not knowing how to get an A in the course.
不知道如何在课程中获得A。
I temporarily thought maybe I should just
我一时想也许我应该
throw myself in front of a car,
直接冲到车前（撞死拉倒）,
it would be easier than this.
这可比考A简单多了。
I lived in an orphanage until I was 10,
我10岁前一直住在孤儿院,
in a series of foster homes.
不断在寄养家庭过活。
The circumstances at that time were such
当时的情况是这样的，
that my father had walked out on his family.
我父亲已经离开了他的家庭。
And I was born in the depression
我出生在大萧条时期。
And my mother was working as a candy girl in Detroit,
母亲在底特律卖糖果，
on the east side of Detroit earning $17 a week.
在其东部地区，周薪17美元。
I can remember a girl named Martha came.
我记得有个叫玛莎的女孩被人送过来。
And they were dropping her off for basically
他们把她送到这里的原因和
the same reasons that we were dropped off there.
我们被送到这里的原因基本相同。
And they said, go find Wayne.
他们说，去找韦恩。
And I came and I started talking to Martha.
然后我来了，开始和玛莎聊天。
And she was crying and she was all upset
之后，她开始哭泣，非常难过，
and she was sad.
而且很伤心。
And I was trying to convince her that
我试图说服她，
she didn't have to be sad.
告诉她不必悲伤。
I remember saying to her this is a great place,
我记得我对她说，“这是个好地方,
there's no parent here.
这里没有家长。
You can do pretty much anything that you want.
你几乎可以做任何你想做的事”。
I mean you've got a lot of freedom
我的意思是说，你有很多自由，
and we're going to have a great time
我们会过得很愉快，
and all you have to do is change the way you think.
你所要做的就是改变你的思维方式。
And it goes from being a miserable experience
把一个悲惨的经历、
or a tough experience or a hard experience
一个艰苦的经历或一个困难的经历
to one that you can do anything that you want with.
变成一个你可以做任何你想做的事情的经历。
In that moment,
在那一刻,
when I watched the building burn
当我看着大楼着火的时候，
I wasn't thinking about all of the work
我没有去想我桌子上
that was piled up on my desk,
堆积的所有东西，
I was thinking about my father's standing next to me,
而是想我父亲就站在我旁边，
I was thinking thank you god that
我在想要感谢上帝，
there was no one in the building.
因为幸好这栋楼里没有人。
And I was also a little too upset about
我只是对我办公室里丢失的
some of the physical items that I was losing in my office.
一些物品感到有点难过罢了。
I had more of a relationship with my adding machine
因为我很忙的缘故，
than some of the people in my life
我与税务加法器的关系比
because of how busy I was.
我生活中的一些人更亲密。
The interesting thing was this is
有趣的是，
where the soul is so wonderfully wise and resilient.
这就是灵魂如此富有智慧和弹性的地方。
I remember watching this fire and
我记得看着这场火灾，
just being devastated by it on one here
看着一切被它摧毁了，
but there was this little voice that said,
但有个小小的声音对我说,
this is happening for a reason,
“这一切都是有原因的,
you don't know why right now and it looks horrible,
你现在不知道为什么，它看起来很可怕，
but there's actually something wonderful
但实际上有一些美好的东西
that's going to come from this, stay awake.
将从这里产生，请保持清醒”。
So I was going to throw away this intuition,
我打算抛弃这种直觉，
throw away this affirmation stuff.
扔掉这些肯定的东西。
Because it was something
因为这是
that I needed to get to be kind of normal.
我需要变得正常的东西。
I got to my sophomore year and
到了二年级，
I started really hitting the wall.
我真的开始碰壁了。
I was doing an md in the phds.
我在攻读博士学位。
So I started blowing disks and stuff.
所以我开始销毁磁盘之类的东西。
And I couldn't end up going in the intellectual
我不能从事我想从事的
career that I wanted to.
知识分子职业。
Being a neurosurgeon because you can't stand up.
因为站不起来，我选择成为一名神经外科医生。
So I chose psychiatry because I would sit down.
我选择了精神病学，因为我可以坐着工作。
And I hated, it was boring.
不过我讨厌这项工作，它很无聊。
But I learned very interesting.
但是我学到了很有趣的东西。
All roads lead back to spirituality and intuition.
所有的道路都回归灵性和直觉。
I go back to my door, my call my parents.
我回到我的家门，打电话给我的父母。
And I say I hate it here, this isn't working for me.
我说我讨厌这里，这里不适合我。
And my father says, quit, so quit,
我父亲说，“退学吧，退学吧,
you can come home.
你回家吧”。
And I changed my mind.
后来我改变主意了。
And in that moment,
在那一刻,
I changed the migraine headaches.
我改变了偏头痛的症状。
I maybe had three or four the rest of my whole life
因为我改变了这种模式，
because I changed this pattern.
我在余生中可能有过三四次这种经历。
And my perception was you must do this and
过去我认为我必须这么做，
I've really been driven my whole life to get it right.
我一生真的被驱使着要把它做好，
and get it right though in the way that the culture and
而且要按照文化和
in my case the practice of medicine says is right.
我的医学实践所说的正确方式来做。
But here's the problem.
但这就是问题所在。
Most of what I was taught in medicine
我在医学上所学到的关于
about what causes disease is not the truth.
疾病原因的大部分内容都不是真理。
I cured my migraine headaches,
我治好了偏头痛，
not with lmitrex, not with Advil.
不是用曲坦类药物lmitrex，也不是用 Advil。
I cured it with a change of perception.
我通过改变观念治愈了它。
Some people think the change has to be shocking,
有些人认为这种变化必须是令人震惊的，
like diving into a cold pool.
就像跳进一个冷水池。
But it can be as simple and easy as
但是它可以简单易行，
letting go of the limiting beliefs you're holding onto.
就像放弃你一直坚持的限制性信念一样。
I can't change...
我不能改变...
We're gonna feel healthy...
我们会觉得很健康...
We can't have the life ,
我们不能过这样的生活，
why we can't stop feeling tired.
为什么我们不能停止感到疲惫！
I can't be happy, .. wanting things that I can change
我无法快乐... ，我想要我可以改变的东西...
I can't!
我做不到！
You can begin your journey wherever you are.
无论你在哪里，你都可以开始你的旅程。
Whenever you want.
随时都可以。
You may be starting your journey from a mansion
你可能是从豪宅或无家可归的收容所
or a homeless shelter.
开启你的旅程。
Wherever you begin,
无论你从哪里开始，
the gateways to wisdom and knowledge are always open.
通往智慧和知识的大门永远是敞开的。
And the first step can be as simple as changing
而第一步可以很简单，
the thought from I can't to I can,
就是把想法从 “我不能” 变成 “我可以”，
I can do it.
以及 “我可以做到这一点” 。
When you get it, that you have so much more
当你明白了这一点时，你对你的生活的
control over your life than you thought you did
掌控比你想象的要多得多，
or control over your experience of your life
或者掌控你的生活经历
it's not the events of your life.
而不把它当成你生命中的重大事件。
There is this sense that is so playful and so joyous
这种感觉是如此的好玩和快乐，
and it begins with changing the way you think.
而它开始于改变你的思维方式。
THE INTERNAL LANDSCAPE OF CHANGE
变化的内部景观
Life as you know, it can change in an instant.
正如你所知道的，生活可以在瞬间改变。
Everything you call god can disappear before your eyes.
所有你称之为神的一切都会在你眼前消失。
And you know it's not until you have a crisis like that
直到你遇到这样的危机，
that you're suddenly you come face to face with
你才会突然直面世界上
what it is that really matters in the world.
真正重要的是什么。
So it's a wonderful thing when you bump up
因此，当碰上一些感觉不舒服的事情时，
against something that feels uncomfortable.
你可以把它认为是一件很美妙的事情。
Because it's this opportunity to now
因为正是现在这个
feel the discomfort of it and work it
让我们感受不适的机会，
into a place of greater comfort,
带领我们去到一个更舒适的地方，
that's how you get rid of those obstacles,
这样你才能摆脱这些障碍，
that's how you let yourself flow
这就是如何让自己
in the way that you want.
以你想要的方式流动。
Okay, I can do this.
是的，我能做到。
I can do it, I can change.
我可以做到，我可以改变。
I can make my life better.
我可以让我的生活变得更好。
I'm scared but I want to change, I do.
我很害怕，但是我想改变，我真的想。
I'm gonna stick with this and I'm gonna try.
我会坚持下去，我会尽力的。
No, no.
不，不。
I am, going to think more positive thoughts.
我要，去多想一些正面积极的想法。
Like, um,
比如,
I am happy,
我很开心,
I am happy.
我很快乐。
Wow, this is not gonna be easy.
这可不容易。
The universe is not responding to your words.
宇宙不会对你的话语有反应。
But your words are reflective of how you feel.
但是你的话语反映了你的感觉。
And how you feel
而你的感觉
is reflective of the vibration that you're offering.
是你所内心振动的反映。
And the vibration that you're offering
你所内在的振动
does equal your point of attraction.
确实等同于你的吸引点。
So paying attention to what you say
因此，留意你所说的话是
is a very powerful tool for
一个非常有力的方法，
understanding what your point of attraction is.
可以帮助了解你的吸引点是什么。
It was on a tour of Australia.
记得在澳大利亚旅行的时候，
and it was one of the first conversations we ever had.
我和露易丝进行了第一次谈话。
And so I was trying to rush her around
我试图催促她，
and no one should rush Louise around two years,
没有人会在两年中一直催促露易丝。
Right time right space,
在合适的时间、合适的地点，
all in its good time,
在一切都是美好的时光里，
type of person.
催促那个合适的人。
And I said, Louise,
我说，“露易丝,
let's do this and let's kill two birds of one stone.
让我们一石二鸟吧”。
And Louise looked at me horrified and said,
露易丝惊恐地看着我说:
why would you want to kill two birds?
“你为什么要杀两只鸟？”。
She always walks a talk.
她总是言行一致。
And everyone around it seems to pick up on that.
而周围的每个人似乎都发现了这一点。
From that moment on,
从那一刻起，
I really was careful in what I said.
我很留心我所说的话。
You know, I stop saying,
我不再说，
I can't stand this,
“我受不了了,
that person is a pain in the neck,
那个人是个讨厌鬼,
or I'm hopeless.
我没有希望了”。
If you can really accept the fact
如果你能真正接受这样一个事实，
that every time you think a thought
即每当你有一个念头，
and every time you speak a word,
每当你说一句话，
you are literally painting your future
你就是在字面上描绘你的未来，
or whatever you want to call it,
或者不管你怎么称呼它，
you are creating and you're creating your own life.
你是在创造，正创造着你自己的生活。
One of the gifts of affirmations,
自我肯定的礼物之一,
the using of affirmations over the years,
多年来我一直运用肯定法，
it's allowed me to experience
它让我体验到生活
living in a state of abundance,
在一个富足的状态中,
living in a state of belief that
生活在一个相信所有我需要的东西
all that I need will come to me when I need it,
都会在我需要的时候来到我身边的状态中，
living in a state of recognition that
生活在这样一种认知状态中，
all that really does matter is love.
即真正重要的是爱。
And it's because of using affirmations over the years,
这是因为多年来使用的自我肯定法，
I find that I'm now more concerned with
我发现我现在更关心生命
life as an energetic force,
作为一种能量的力量，
living in an energetic state of those affirmations
生活在那些肯定的能量状态中，
instead of the actual words.
而不只是停留在口头语言上。
To begin with, you start by what we
首先，你可以从做我们所说的
call doing affirmations.
自我肯定法开始。
And that is making positive statements about your life
那就是对你的生活做出积极的陈述，
and you do them deliberately.
并且你是有意识地去做。
You might do them in the morning,
你可以在早上做，
you might do them at noon,
可以在中午做，
you might do them at night.
也可以在晚上做。
And as you start to do them,
当你开始做的时候，
things will begin to change,
事情就会开始改变，
maybe on a very small level.
也许是在一个非常小的层面上。
I call it getting the green lights in the parking places.
我称之为停车场绿灯。
The affirmations,
自我肯定法，
get you into that space where you are ready
让你进入那个你已经准备好
to recognize the healer that you need,
认出你需要的治疗者的空间，
recognize the teacher that you need,
认出那个你需要的老师，
recognize the philosophy that will work best for you.
认出那个最适合你的哲学。
Doing an affirmation is either writing it down,
在做自我肯定法时，你可以把它写下来，
writing it on the wall or the mirror
写在墙上或者镜子上，
or just saying it.
或者直接说出来。
My body now restores itself
我的身体现在可以自行恢复
to its natural state of good health.
到自然的健康状态。
I'm strong fit and vibrant all the time every day.
我每天都很强壮健壮，一直都很有活力。
I'm in the film I work in play.
我在电影里自如演戏。
My partner for life has arrived today.
今天我会遇到我的终生伴侣。
And wealth is here to stay.
财富不请自来。
My income is constantly increasing.
我的收入在不断增加。
On infinite, I'm immortal, I'm universal.
从无限角度上来说，我是不朽的，遍布一切的。
I'm infinite, I'm immortal, I'm universal.
我是无限的，不朽的，遍布一切的。
I do the work I love.
我做我喜欢的工作。
I work within for people I really like.
我在为我真正喜欢的人工作。
And I'm earning good money.
而且我赚了不少钱。
Now you don't have to have a specific job,
你不用做特定的工作,
but under that banner
但是在...下，
a lot of good could come into your life.
你的生活会充满美好。
I am passionate about life.
我对生活充满热情。
I love myself.
我爱我自己。
I am well.
我很好。
And then I bet you I said it three or 400 times a day
我跟你打赌，为了克服对癌症的恐惧，
to get over the fear of having cancer.
我一天要说三四百次。
And I believe that,
我相信它，
not only saying it but actually believing it.
不仅仅是说说而已，而是真的相信它。
The affirmations are just the starting point,
自我肯定法只是起点,
that's like going okay, here's where the goal is.
这就像是说”好吧”，这就是目标。
What really gives those affirmations power
真正赋予这些自我肯定力量的是
is the emotion we put behind it.
我们在其背后所投注其中的情感。
So what's interesting is you start out the journey,
有趣的是你开始了这段旅程，
going okay,
一切顺利，
let me start here.
让我从这里开始。
Step one is what's the affirmation.
第一步，自我肯定的是什么。
Step two is you know how can I generate
第二步，我怎样才能产生
the emotional power behind that affirmation.
该自我肯定背后的情感力量。
And a lot of that comes from taking actions
很多这些都来自于采取行动来
to support that affirmation.
支持这个肯定。
That's how you begin to step into that state.
这就是你开始进入那种状态的方式。
And then as you step into that state and you take actions
然后，当你进入这种状态，你采取行动，
and you put the emotional power
你把情感的力量注入
behind those affirmations,
到这些自我肯定后面，
they begin to manifest themselves in your life.
然后它们开始在你的生活中显现出来。
It's got to get anchored into your,
它必须扎根于你，
not only your mind but in your spirit
不仅仅是你的思想，还有你的灵性，
and you have to believe it.
而且你必须相信它。
And when you're first doing it,
当你第一次做的时候，
it feels fake, it feels silly.
你可能会感觉很假很傻。
But after a while you start to realize, yeah,
但过了一段时间你开始意识到，
you know, that's right, that's yeah.
是的，没错，就是这样。
What I like people to do
我喜欢让人们做的
is to stand in front of a mirror
就是站在镜子前，
and do their affirmations.
做“自我肯定”。
Because there's something very powerful about
当你看着自己的眼睛，
looking in your own eyes and accepting yourself
接受自己或者注意到拒绝自己，
or noticing that you reject yourself
对自己说一些积极的话的时候，
when you're saying something positive about yourself.
会有一些非常强大的东西在其中。
Driving to work when I first meet Louise I used to...
第一次见到路易丝的时候，我是在开车的路上...
She said, no, that you should 20,000 times a day
她说，不，你一天说两万次，或者
or every time you have a negative thought, just,
每次你有消极的想法，就说：
I love and approve of myself,
“我爱我自己，也赞同我自己”,
just to replace it with that.
把之前的肯定句换成这个。
The longest time
这是我说
I love and I love and
“我爱自己，我爱自己”最长的一次，
I couldn't think of the other word it was like.
我想不出另一个词是什么样子。
Why can't I remember such a simple word.
为什么我生命中没有忆起这么简单的一个词！
It is like planting a seed in the ground.
这就像在地里播下一粒种子。
It's not necessarily true at the moment,
目前不一定是真的，
but it is something you want to have be true.
但它是你想让它成为真之物。
So you put the seed in and you expect it to grow.
你把种子放进去，你期望它能生长。
You don't wait for two days and then
你不会只等两天，
dig in the earth and say what's happening,
就开始挖土，看看长得怎么样,
what's happening.
瞅瞅发生了什么。
You expect that thing to grow because
你期待种子能够成长，
you know there's a law in a process.
因为你知道这个过程中有一条法则。
And the seed will grow if it is in the right soil
如果种子生长在适当的土壤中，
and it has the right amount of moisture.
并且含有适量的水分，它就会茁壮生长。
And many people are finding out about how literal,
很多人都发现，
this language is in very interesting ways.
这种语言的表达方式非常有趣。
I hear people say that,
我听人们这么说，
they want a perfect relationship where they want
他们想要完美的关系，
abundance in their lives.
他们想要丰盛的人生。
And they say it with an air as if
他们说话的神气就好像
they have just put that manifestation out there
他们已经把这种表现方式公之于众了，
and they're going to do it pretty quickly.
而且他们会很快完成。
And then I see them a year later and
但一年后我看到他们时，
it still hasn't happened.
这种情况仍然没有发生。
And a couple years later, it hasn't happened.
几年后，这种情况依旧没有发生。
The field is literal, the divine matrix is literal.
场是字面上的，无量之网是字面上的。
So when you say I want this to happen in my life.
所以当你说，我希望这一切发生在我的生活中。
The field says, okay.
这个场会说，好吧。
And I'll let you want and want and want,
我会让你 “想要、想要、想要”，
because there's no outcome,
因为没有提议结果如何,
it's an open ended proposition.
这只是个开放式的提议。
It is like a computer,
它就像一台电脑，
if you have this gorgeous computer put in front of you
如果你把这台漂亮的电脑放在面前，
and you don't know what to do with it,
而你不知道该怎么用它，
it's a piece of junk.
那它就是一堆垃圾。
But if you learn the language of the computer,
但是如果你学会了计算机的语言，
miracles happen.
就会发生奇迹。
I HAVE UNLIMITED POTENTIAL
我有无限的潜力
When I left corporations,
我离开公司的时候，
early 1990,
那是在1990年初，
I found myself in high deserts
我来到了新墨西哥州北部沙漠，
of northern new Mexico where I live today.
也就是我今天居住的地方。
I'm a beautiful part of the world.
那里风景优美。
And during that time,
在那段时间里，
it was one of the worst droughts in recorded history
出现了美国西南部沙漠有史以来
in the American desert southwest.
最严重的干旱之一。
And a native friend called me one day.
一天一个当地的朋友打电话给我。
And he said, Greg, would you like to join me at a place.
他说：“葛雷格，你愿意和我一起去个地方吗？”。
And I love this language.
我喜欢他下面所说的话。
He said, "a place where the skin
他说，“在两个世界间隔膜
between the worlds is really thin to pray rain".
真的很薄的地方，去祈求雨水”。
And he didn't have to ask me twice, I said you bet so.
而且他没有问我第二次，我就说，你说的没错。
We met at an agreed location.
我们在约定的地点见面。
We hiked 135,000 acres of the most beautiful high
我们徒步走过了135,000英亩的
desert sage, we came to a stone circle
最美丽的高沙漠沙地，来到了一个石头圈，
that had been there for so long.
这个石头圈已经存在了很久。
He didn't even know
他甚至不知道
who would place the stones there before him.
之前是谁把这些石头放在那里的。
And I wasn't prepared for what I saw
我接下去所看到的完全超出我预料之外，
because my friend David took his old work shoes off,
我的朋友大卫把他的破工作鞋脱掉，
he put his naked feet inside of this circle.
赤脚走入这个圆圈里。
He closed his eyes and the first
他闭上眼睛，
thing he did was he honored all his ancestors,
做的第一件事就是向他所有的祖先致敬，
he literally said the words.
他真的说了那些话。
He said, all of my ancestors,
他说，“祖先在上,
all of my ancestors, with me now, with me now.
祖先在上，与我一起，与我一起”。
About 20 seconds later,
大约20秒后，
he looked at me and said,
他看着我说，
"I'm hungry, you want to go get a bite to eat?".
“我饿了，你想去吃点东西吗?”。
And I said, well, sure.
然后我说，当然可以。
But I said, "I thought you were going to pray for rain".
我接着说，“我以为你是来祈雨的”。
And he looked at me and he said,
他看着我说,
"No, so if I prayed for rain,
“不是的，如果我祈雨,
rain could never happen.
就不可能下雨。
Because the moment we pray for something to occur,
因为当我们祈祷某事发生的时候，
we've just implied we've acknowledged it's not there now.
我们就已经暗示承认它并不存在。
And we may be empowering the very condition
我们可能正在赋予我们想要改变的
that we'd like to change".
状况以权力”。
And I said,
我说,
"If you didn't just pray for rain in those 20 seconds,
“如果在那20秒钟中，你没有在祈雨，
what did you do?".
那你在干吗?”。
And he said,  "When I close my eyes,
他说，“当我一闭眼,
I felt the feeling of what it feels like to stand with my feet,
我体验到双脚站立并
naked in the mud in our ... village.
赤身踩在我们村里泥地中的感觉。
And the mud's there,
泥巴就在那里，
because there's been so much rain".
因为下了这么多雨”。
And he said, "I smelled the smells,
然后他说，“我闻到了气味，
of what it smells like when the rain
闻到了当雨水落到泥土
falls off the earth and walls of our ... village.
和我们村庄的墙上时的味道。
And I felt the feeling of what it feels like to run
我感受到了跑过玉米地的感觉，
through the fields of corn and the corn is there
那里有玉米，
and it's so high because there's been so much rain".
因为下了太多的雨，所以玉米长得很高”。
He said, "I gave thanks of gratitude and appreciation
他说:：“我对已经下过的雨
for the rain that's already happened".
表示感谢和感激”。
When you speak an affirmation,
当你说自我肯定时,
even though at first when you speak the affirmation,
尽管一开始当你说自我肯定的时候，
you may not believe it.
你可能不相信它。
In time as you speak it,
随着时间推移，当你说出来时，
you come into the allowing of it.
你开始允许它发挥作用了。
And of course there are many people
当然也有很多人
speaking affirmations
在说自我肯定语，
who are not receiving what they are speaking
但他们并没有接收到他们所说的东西，
because they are using words
因为他们只使用话语，
and wanting the words to make it so.
并希望这些话语能成为现实。
But the universe does not respond to your words,
但宇宙并不回应你的话语，
the universe responds to your vibration.
宇宙回应的是你的振动。
And your emotions indicate what your vibration is.
而你的情绪表明你的振动是什么。
Affirmations are magnified
如果我们在梦中使用自我肯定语，
if we use them in our dream state.
那么其作用会被放大。
Because at that moment the ego is asleep,
因为在那一刻，小我沉睡了，
the logical mind is resting.
逻辑头脑在休眠中。
And therefore you have a perfect opportunity
因此，你有一个完美的机会
to program your future.
来规划你的未来。
Your program your mind with these positive affirmations.
你用这些积极的自我肯定语对你的头脑进行编程。
Our dreams are there to resolve conflicts
我们的梦是用来解决
between the conscious and the unconscious
有意识和无意识之间的冲突的，
and they dare to regulate our moods.
它们可以用于调节我们的情绪。
But what if you went to sleep
但是如果你睡觉的时候
believing that you were all as well, you are safe,
相信自己是安全的，一切都会在
everything will appear at the right time
合适的时间出现，在应该出现的时候出现，
when it's supposed to.
那会怎么样呢？
And I think that would be very good
我认为，如果你们都决定这样做，
if you all decided that too.
那就非常好。
That the decade you are in at the moment
你此刻所处的十年是
is the best decade of your life so far.
迄今为止最美好的十年。
I can do it, you can do it.
我能做到，你也能做到。
I was a high school dropout,
我高中辍学,
had never studied anything,
从来没有学过任何东西，
suddenly became fascinated with this idea
突然对这样一个想法着迷了:
that if I could change my thinking I could change my life.
即如果我能改变我的思维，我就能改变我的生活。
And I started to study and I couldn't stop.
我开始研究，根本停不下来。
I did a lot of classes lots of books.
我上了很多课，读了很多书。
All sorts of things so I could begin to
研究各种各样的事情，这样我才能
understand how this works.
开始理解这是怎么回事。
And at the end of three years I was eligible to become
三年后，我有资格成为他们在教会中
what they called in the church, a licensed practitioner,
所说的有执照的从业人员，
which gave me the opportunity
这让我有机会和其他人
to work 1 on 1 with other people.
进行一对一地的工作。
And that's I think when the
我认为这就是
changes really started to happen because
变化真正开始发生的时候，
I sort of began to teach other people how to do this
因为我开始教别人怎么做
and how to change their thinking
以及如何改变他们的思维，
so they could change their life.
这样他们就可以改变自己的人生。
People were getting good results working with me.
人们和我一起工作得到了很好的结果。
And then I started teaching classes
然后我开始教课，
and those turned out very well.
那些课的效果非常好。
And the next thing I knew
接下来我知道的就是，
I was doing weekend workshops for 350 people.
我当时要为350个人举办周末工作坊。
So one of the things
我开始
I began to really notice was what people said,
注意到的一件事就是人们说了什么，
how they said it and what was wrong in their body.
他们是怎么说的，以及他们的身体出了什么问题。
And I started to put things together
我开始把事情组织起来，
and I really trained my mind to listen to what people said.
我用心训练我的头脑去倾听别人说了些什么。
I put a list together for my own use
我把一份清单放在一起，
with clients and I'd alphabetized it.
按字母顺序排列，供我自己与客户使用。
So if you came in with a problem,
如果你来的时候有什么问题,
I could look it up quickly and
我可以很快地在这份清单上查一下，
see what I had written about it.
看看其中我写了些什么。
And I showed it to a friend in class
我在课堂上给一个朋友看，
and she said to me, "Oh, Louise, what a great idea,
她对我说，“哦，露易丝，这主意太棒了,
why don't you make a little book out of it?".
你为什么不把它做成一本小册子呢?”。
And, "Oh. Really?  A book?".
“哦，真的吗? 一本书?”。
So my first little book was done in 1976
我的第一本小书是在1976年完成的，
that was 'Heal your body'.
叫做《疗愈你的身体》。
And that was the mental patterns
这本书讲的是
for the physical ailments in the bodies
身体疾病的心理模式，
and how to make changes.
以及如何做出改变。
I really believe that the big boys as I call them,
我很确信，我所说的那些大人物,
would not publish the book and if they did,
是不会出版这本书的，如果他们出版了,
they probably would want to change it.
他们可能想要改变其中的内容。
Because my ideas at that time were very radical,
因为我当时的想法非常激进，
your thinking can change your life.
即你的思维可以改变你的人生。
And I wanted to say it the way I wanted to say it,
我希望用我想说的方式来表达，
I didn't want a word change,
我不想改变其中的内容，
because I knew what I was doing.
因为我知道自己在做什么。
So I printed the book myself.
我自己打印了这本书。
So I went to the church printer
我去了教堂的印刷厂，
because I didn't know where else to go.
因为我不知道还能去哪里打印。
And I had this little 12 page pamphlet put together.
我把这本12页的小册子装订在一起。
And I remember taking it to my teacher
我记得我把它
and showing it to him.
拿给我的老师看。
And he said, "Oh, Louise, is that sweet,
他说:：“哦，路易丝，这很好,
what a nice thing you've done!
你做了一件很棒的事！
How many did you have printed, 200?".
你印了多少，200本吗?”。
And I said, "No, 5000!".
我说，“不，5000本!”。
He went,
他说,
"You're crazy, you'll never sell that thing".
“你疯了吗，你永远也卖不掉那东西的”。
But two years later I had sold 5000.
但两年后，我卖出了5000本。
I sent a free coffee to every metaphysical church that
我给每一个我所知道的形而上学教会
what I could knew of and an order form.
送去了免费的咖啡和一份订货单。
And many of them took it.
他们中的许多人都订货了。
And that was my first little book.
那是我的第一本小书。
I read her little book and
我读了露易丝的小书，
I said this would never work for me.
我说这对我没用。
But I came home determined to try it.
但我回到家后，决定试一下。
At the time I was being treated for
当时我正在接受
Fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue.
纤维肌痛和慢性疲劳的治疗。
I was self employed.
我是自由职业者。
My energy was, levels were so low,
我的能量水平很低，
I was barely putting in 20h a week,
我一周勉强投入20小时工作，
completely ignoring my children and my responsibilities.
完全无视我的孩子和我的责任。
And I started her affirmation.
然后我开始实践书中的自我肯定法。
My body now restores itself
我的身体现在自行恢复
to its natural state of good health.
到了健康的自然状态。
And I saw the difference in a week.
我在一周内就看到了不同。
I said it all the time.
我一直都这么说。
And I started doing her mirror work.
然后我开始做露易丝书中的镜子练习。
I would go to the mirror
我会走到镜子前，
and though I didn't feel it
尽管我没有感觉，
and the word stuck in my throat.
而且我要说的词还卡在我的喉咙里。
I would look in the mirror and I would say:
我会对着镜子说:
"I love you very much, Jackie!
“我非常爱你，杰基！
You're perfect exactly the way you are".
你现在的样子就是完美的”。
All right.
好吧。
This is going well.
一切都很顺利。
I have all the power.
我拥有改变自我的所有力量。
And nothing can stop me and I feel healthy.
没有什么可以阻止我，我感觉很健康。
I'm breathing and air feels really good.
我在呼吸，空气感觉非常好。
And accepting that I'm a part of the universe and
接受我是宇宙的一部分，
it gives me exactly what I asked for.
它给我的正是我想要的。
Okay, so, I totally tripped.
好吧，我完全被绊倒了。
It's alright.
没关系。
There's a positive trip.
这是一次积极的旅行。
CHALLENGES ALONG THE WAY
一路上的挑战
In the moments of deepest despair,
在最绝望的时刻，
there's actually humor.
其实也可以有幽默感。
Always humor lifts us up to god,
幽默总是把我们提升到神面前，
it lightens up every situation.
它会让每个情况都变得轻松。
But do you just before you get there?
但是在你到达那里之前呢？
There's usually this time of pain filled joy
通常会有这种充满痛苦的喜悦
or joy filled pain.
或充满喜悦的痛苦的时候。
Where you might have to break down
在那里你可能不得不
with some deep sobs.
深深地啜泣。
But when someone's in trouble,
当有人遇到麻烦时，
I think of them just like
我觉得他们就像
someone has come out of a movie, a scary movie.
从恐怖电影里走出来的人。
And they cried.
他们看电影时哭了。
Their tears are real,
他们的眼泪是真实的，
their fear is real,
他们的恐惧是真实的，
but what they saw that cause the fear is not real,
但是他们看到的导致恐惧的东西并不真实，
it's a movie.
而是部电影。
So what I'll do is I offer some suggestions about
我会做的就是提供一些建议，
ways to reframe their situation or
帮助他们重构自己的处境，
find a blessing in a seeming problem.
或者在看似有问题的情况下找到幸福。
And yes,
是的,
there are challenges in life that we all go through
生活中我们都经历过很多挑战，
and there's no shame with that.
这没什么好羞愧的。
But it's what you do with the challenges that counts.
但重要的是你如何应对挑战。
Now that I know when so called negative things happen
现在我知道当所谓的消极事情发生时，
that they really positive things.
它们其实是积极的信号。
And then what I need to do
然后我需要做的
is focus on a positive outcome
就是专注于一个积极的结果，
and then stay course.
然后坚持到底。
And then so shall I have that experience.
然后我也会有那样的经历。
The way that you retrain yourself is
你重新训练自己的方法是，
to shift from having a fear to having a curiosity.
是从心怀恐惧转变为心怀好奇。
Substitute the word curiosity for the word fear.
用好奇代替恐惧。
Because a lot of us
因为我们很多人
when we start doing those things to honor our soul
开始做这些事情是为了尊重我们的灵魂
or to express our creativity,
或者表达我们的创造力,
those are really vulnerable acts.
这些都是非常脆弱的行为。
The things that we intend are that we affirm
我们打算为我们的生活
for our lives are those things
申明的东西是那些
that are deeply important to our soul
对我们的灵魂非常非常重要的东西，
and so they're vulnerable.
所以它们是脆弱的。
And too often we turn to people who just squash them
我们经常求助于那些压制他们的人，
or who tell you why it isn't gonna work
或者那些告诉你为什么这不会有效，
or why that's a crazy affirmation
或者为什么这是一个疯狂的肯定，
or that's a crazy intention.
或者这是一个疯狂的意图的人。
That's called going to the hardware store for milk.
这叫做去五金店买牛奶，找错了人。
You want to go to the people
你想去找那些真正
who are really going to hold your hand on the journey,
会在旅途中牵着你手的人,
and say, "Hey, I'm bit right there with you".
然后说，“嘿，我就在你身边”。
Awareness is the first step in healing or changing.
觉察是疗愈或改变的第一步。
When you're facing challenges on the journey,
当你在旅途中遇到挑战时，
it's tempting to turn back
会很想回头，
or to blame somebody for the situation.
或者把该情况归咎于某人。
The healing attitude though is to think of
不过，疗愈的态度是把
any external challenge as simply a reflection
任何外在挑战看作是
of your own internal resistance to change.
你内在对改变的抵制的简单反映。
I'm sure everyone I know think I'm totally nuts.
我相信我认识的每个人都认为我疯了。
And they're right.
他们是对的。
I'll never make it through this.
我永远也过不了这一关。
I'll probably flake out like I always do.
我可能会像往常一样退缩。
Besides this isn't even doing any good anyway.
此外，这甚至没有任何好处。
Before the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries,
在十五和十六世纪以前,
all of the ships were made out of wood.
所有的船都是木头做的。
Not because iron wasn't available
不是因为没有铁，
and steel wasn't available,
或者没有钢,
but because there was a belief that wood floated.
而是因为人们相信木头会漂浮。
So therefore you had to make
所以人们必须用
ships out of things that floated.
能飘浮在水面上的东西来造船。
And then someone came along and said that,
后来有人走过来说，
"It has absolutely nothing to do
“这与东西是由什么做成的
with what things are made out of,
完全没有关系，
it has to do with them out of water that is being dispersed,
它与船体排水量有关，
that's what determines whether something will float in it".
而这就是决定船体是否会漂浮在水中的原因"。
And I think about that all the time because
我一直在思考这个问题，
it's in the contemplation of what you desire
因为正是对你所渴望的东西沉思冥想时，
that you create what it is
你创造了
that you want to have for yourself.
你自己想要的东西。
The law of flotation was not discovered by
浮力定律并不是通过
the contemplation of the sinking of things.
对事物的沉降的冥思苦想而发现的。
信念
I mean, come on,
我是说，拜托,
I'm not one of these self-help people.
我不是那种自助人。
And I don't believe in crystals and white light and
我也不相信水晶、白光、
divine feminine and angels and source energy.
神圣女性、天使和能量之源。
And what is that?
那些都是什么东东啊？
Let's be realistic.
让我们现实一点吧。
This is all just beautiful thinking.
这些都是美好的想法。
We tend to live our lives based on what we believe
我们倾向于根据我们对自己、我们的世界、
about ourselves, our world, our capabilities and our limits.
我们的能力和我们的限制的信念来生活。
Where do those beliefs come from?
这些信念从何而来？
More often not they come from
大多数的信念
what other people have told us,
并不是来自于别人已告诉我们的，
history, science, religion, culture, family.
而是来自于历史、科学、宗教、文化和家庭。
What if they're wrong?
如果他们错了呢？
And all these people tell me what to do
所有这些人都告诉我该做什么，
and then please, if it were for my mom...
不过拜托，如果这些是为了我妈妈...
I had at least have a chance.
我至少还有机会。
I mean, come on,
我是说，拜托,
where was Louise Hay when I was growing up?
当我成长的时候，路易斯 · 海在哪里？
I had no one to show me the way to be.
没有人告诉我该怎么做。
And my dad is no Wayne Dyer.
我爸爸也不是韦恩 · 戴尔。
I can tell you that much.
我可以告诉你这么多。
Anything you complain about,
无论你抱怨什么，
repetitively is something
重复性出现的是
that you have an unconscious intention to produce.
你背后无意识的意图所产生的东西。
SELF CONCEPTS
自我概念
And now, just too old to change my life.
现在，我太老了，无力改变我的生活。
That's it.
就是这样。
Too old, lazy.
太老了，太懒。
... did
I should have tried to be positive years ago.
我几年前就应该试着积极一点。
I think it really starts with
我认为这真的
realizing that you don't love yourself.
要从意识到你不爱自己开始。
That most people don't.
大多数人都没有意识到这一点。
Most people feel they're not good enough,
大多数人觉得自己不够好，
they haven't done it right,
他们没有做对，
they won't do it right,
也不会做对，
they'll never be enough
觉得永远都不够，
and they're definitely not lovable.
而且一点也不可爱。
And when we come from that space,
当我们内心处于那种状态时，
it's very hard to create things
就很难为自己
for ourselves that are really good.
创造出真正好的东西。
-*- Denail(否定） -*-
Things weren't so bad before.
以前的情况并不是那么糟糕。
There's something wrong with me.
我有点不对劲。
I'm fine, I'm fine the way, I am...
我很好，一路上我很好，我...
I think it's fine the way it was.
我觉得这样挺好的。
And I went here sort of disdain the same.
而我到这里也有点不屑一顾。
Everything was messed up and confused.
一切都变得一团糟，混乱不堪。
Well, at least I know what to expect here.
好吧，至少我知道在这里可以期待什么。
It may not be the best
这可能不是最好的，
but at least I know how to handle this.
但至少我知道如何处理这个问题。
And what's in the future might be worse,
未来的情况可能更糟，
so I better not try and go out there and change things.
所以我最好按兵不动，不要尝试去改变事情。
What if I fail, what if I don't succeed?
如果我失败了怎么办，如果我没有成功怎么办?
-*- Delaying tactics（延迟策略）-*-
I should just go back and I have no time for this.
我应该回去了，我没有时间做这个事。
I mean I have so much to do.
我的意思是，我还有很多事情要做。
I'll come back later, I'll do it later.
我一会儿再来，一会儿再做。
I hvae job, all these important things.
我要打工，还有一大堆重要的事情要做。
I gotta go, I just I have to go.
我得走了，真的得走了。
A lot of times,
很多时候,
we're missing information
我们漏掉了下一步
about what the next step might be
可能是什么的信息，
in terms of the action equation of affirmations
根据自我肯定加上行动
plus actions equals miracles, right,
等于奇迹这个公式，
a lot of times we're missing information about
很多时候，我们忽略了要做什么以及
what to do, how to take action.
如何采取行动的信息。
But we call it something else like I must be afraid,
我们称它为别的东西，比如我一定很害怕，
that's why I'm stuck.
这就是我被困住的原因。
What if I lose my friends and family doing this stuff?
如果我失去了朋友和家人，那该怎么办？
People are gonna think I'm crazy.
人们会认为我疯了。
People are gonna find out that
人们会发现我
I'm involved in some weird psychological thing
被卷入了一些奇怪的心理问题，
and they're all gonna laugh.
他们都会笑话我的。
I just wanna go home and sit right.
我只想回家好好待着。
It doesn't feel right.
我感觉不对劲。
Where am I?
我这是在哪儿？
We have been conditioned to feel
我们已经习惯于
the feelings of the things
感受生活中我们
that we don't want in life and that we're afraid of.
不想要的东西和我们害怕的东西的感觉。
We wake up in the morning and we see the 6:00 news.
我们早上醒来，看到6点钟的新闻。
And then we go through our day saying,
然后我们每天都在说，
"Oh, I hope I'm not going to see that today
“哦，我希望我今天不会看到这个，
or I hope it's not around the corner
或者我希望它不在拐角处，
where do we learn to feel the things that we don't want
我们从哪里学会去感受我们不想要的东西
rather than things that we choose to have".
而不是选择我们要拥有的东西”。
If you can just remember that any time,
如果你随时都按这种方式行事，
something feels uncomfortable.
那么你会感到不舒服。
Just stop where you are and acknowledge that
只要你停下脚步，承认这只是
it's just a matter of reaching for better feeling, thoughts,
一个达到更好的感觉、想法的问题,
reaching for a feeling of relief works,
寻求一种解脱的、
the resistance out of everything.
一切阻力都会消失的感觉。
A client of mine in a neighboring state called me up.
邻州的一个客户给我打了电话。
And he was really really depressed and suicidal.
他非常沮丧，甚至有自杀倾向。
I asked him,
我问他，
if during the course of the day
在这一天里，
he had seen anything that he could do
你能否做一些对他人
that would be a positive contribution to somebody.
有积极贡献的任何事情。
And he thought about it for a long time.
他对此想了很久。
And he said, well,
他说，好吧,
there's an elderly lady
我公寓楼下
that lives in the apartment below me.
住着一位老太太。
When I came home today,
我今天回家的时候,
I saw that the area in front of her apartment was dirty
看到她公寓前面的地很脏，
and needed sweeping.
需要清扫一下。
I said, okay,
我说，好吧,
don't even ring her doorbell or anything like that,
不要按她的门铃或者告诉她,
just take your broom down there.
带把扫帚下去吧。
I'll stay on the phone right now,
我现在不挂电话，
go down with your broom and clean that area, I'll wait.
你拿着扫帚下去把那个地方打扫干净，我会在线等你。
And so he was gone for 10 or 15 minutes.
他去那里扫了10或15分钟。
Finally he came back
最后他回来了，
and it was like a different person.
就像变了一个人。
He had made this thing happen.
他让自己发生了蜕变。
He had gotten out of himself enough
他已经完全摆脱了小我，
to make a contribution.
为他人做出了贡献。
And that started this flow of positive energy.
而这个改变开启了正能量的流动。
He was completely different
当我在电话中再次听到他的声音时，
and I heard his voice come back on the line.
我感觉他已脱胎换骨。
And so, that kind of thing lets me know that
这样的事情让我了解到，
it's possible to live your life that way,
我们可以这样生活,
that it's possible to live your life
我们可以把自己的生命
kind of on the contribution side and
投入到贡献中，
let it be okay to receive back also.
而且可以欢喜地接受回报。
What's wrong with me?
我到底怎么了？
What am I not doing right?
我哪里做得不对?
I'm doing the inner work.
我正在做内在的功课。
Where's the reward?
奖励在哪里？
Keep thinking the positive things.
继续思考积极的事情吧。
I keep being specific.
我一直关注现实面的东西。
And I'm not moving forward.
而我一直停滞不前。
Fine.
好吧。
Maybe I won't forward at all.
也许我根本就不会进步。
I just sit here.
我只想待在这里。
And not move at all.
一动不动就好。
How do you like that?
你觉得怎么样？
Am with whom I talking to anyway?
我到底是在和谁说话?
TESTING THE DEPTH OF YOUR COMMITMENT
测试你承诺的力度
I was diagnosed with cancer.
我被诊断出患有癌症。
And it was vaginal cancer.
是阴道癌。
And when you look back at my childhood,
当我回顾我的童年,
with the rapes and all the other childhood abuse.
我被人强奸过，还有其它的童年虐待。
And you realize that one of the mental
我意识到导致癌症的
causes for cancer is resentment,
心理原因之一就是怨恨，
deep resentment that is held very strong
深深的怨恨，这种怨恨非常强烈，
till it literally eats away in the body.
直到它逐渐侵蚀身体。
So where would I put my cancer?
那么我该把癌症安放何处呢？
So I remember being very terrified like anybody would.
我记得当时非常害怕，就像任何人都会有的害怕一样。
And I called my teacher and I said,
我打电话给我的老师，我对他说，
Eric, they say I have cancer.
“艾瑞克，他们说我得了癌症”。
And the first thing he said to me is, who is they.
他对我说的第一件事就是，“他们是谁”。
And I said, the doctors.
我说，“是医生们”。
And he said,
他说:
Louise, you could not have done all this
“路易丝，你不可能为了死于癌症
work on yourself to die of cancer,
而在自己身上做所有这些工作,
now let's take a positive approach.
现在让我们采取积极的方法”。
And I clung to that.
我紧紧抓住艾瑞克说的这一点。
It was a lifeline for me.
那是我的救命稻草。
And I did things I hadn't done before.
我做了以前从未做过的事情。
I went from being a junk food person to
我从一个吃垃圾食品的人
doing nutritional work and
变成了做营养工作、
detoxifying my body and I was detoxifying my mind.
为我的身体排毒并为我的思想排毒的人。
And I did a lot of things.
我还做了很多事情。
I had tools to work with.
我有工具可以使用。
And I said to myself,
我对自己说,
you're being given an opportunity
我得到了一个实践
to practice what you're teaching,
你所教的东西的机会，
you're telling people that they can heal anything
你在告诉人们，只要他们愿意，他们可
if they're willing to do the work.
以疗愈任何东西。
And now it's your turn.
现在轮到你了。
I remember working with
我记得和治疗师
the therapist and banging pillows.
一起工作，其中有敲打枕头练习。
And you know getting anger out and all that stuff.
也就是发泄愤怒之类的练习。
But I think that the work I did at the time that was
但我认为当时对我来说
the most important for me was to do forgiveness.
最重要的工作就是宽恕。
And I began to investigate the childhoods of my parents.
我开始调查我父母的童年。
And when I found discovered their stories,
当我发现他们的陈年往事时,
I could understand where they were coming from.
我能理解他们是从哪里来的。
There was just horrendous things on both sides all sides.
他们双方都发生了可怕的事情。
So how could they know how to treat a little child
所以，当他们不能善待自己时，
when they weren't treated that well themselves.
怎么可能知道如何去善待一个小孩子。
So as I began to do the forgiveness work and
于是我开始进行宽恕、
the therapy and the nutrition and everything.
治疗、营养和其它相关的一切工作。
Within six months,
六个月内,
I was able to get the medical establishment
我得以让医疗机构确认
to agree with what I already knew inside
我在内心早已知道的事情，
that I no longer had cancer.
即我不再罹患癌症了。
And when that happened,
当这一切发生时,
I knew that anything could be healed.
我知道任何事情都是可以治愈的。
I knew because I had done it myself
我知道这一点，因为我自己就做过这件事，
and all the other stuff helped.
所有其他的事情都有所帮助。
But I knew that what
但是我知道我
all the affirmations and all the stuff I was doing.
所做的所有的肯定和所有的事情。
So that gave me an extraordinarily strong belief.
所以这给了我一个非常强烈的信念。
And when you have a strong belief you can do anything.
当你有了坚定的信念，你就可以做任何事情。
I was diagnosed with a condition inside of my body
我被诊断出体内有一种疾病，
where a doctor told me that something
医生告诉我，有东西正在
was growing a cancer's tumor that shouldn't be there.
一个本不该长肿瘤的地方长着。
And I have gone I trusted the medical system
我信任医疗系统，
because that's our culture, that's the way we're raised.
因为这是我们的文化，这是我们被抚养的方式。
And there's a part of us that says,
我们内心有一部分在说，
even if I go the holistic route,
即使我选择了整体疗法，
I'm going to let a medical person
我还是会去找医生，
tell me what's going on,
让医生告诉我发生了什么，
just for that validation.
只是为了确认一下。
So it was my opportunity
所以我有机会
to put in the practice everything I ever learned
把我所学到的一切都付诸实践，
and rather than concentrating on something
而不是专注于
that should not be in my body.
不应该出现在我身上的东西。
I began feeling that my body was vital and healthy
我开始觉得我的身体是充满活力和健康的，
rather than focusing on making something change.
而不是专注于去做出一些改变。
However,
然而,
through the influence of family and friends,
通过家庭和朋友的影响,
I underwent a medical procedure anyway.
我还是做了一个医疗手术。
I went into the operating room, I was anesthetized.
我走进手术室，被麻醉了。
And the next I remember I woke up
接下来，我记得我醒过来后，
and there was a doctor looking at me and he said,
有一个医生来看我，他说,
what are you doing here,
“你在这儿干什么,
there's nothing there".
里面什么都没有”。
All I done were the practices and the principles that
我所做的都是我穿越半个地球去
I traveled halfway around the world to learn.
学习的实践和原则。
And I employed it in my own life
我在我自己的生活中应用了它们，
and it worked in that moment.
并且在那一刻起了作用。
I had the photograph showing
我的照片显示
there's nothing in my body.
我身体里什么都没有。
I was anesthetized,
我被麻醉了,
and they didn't exploratory for no reason at all.
而且他们也没有无缘无故地进行调查。
Because of that I can speak with conviction,
正因为如此，我可以坚定地说，
I can look anyone, a scientist,
我可以调查任何人，科学家,
a doubting audience member.
一个多疑的观众。
And I can look them in the eye with conviction and say,
我可以坚定地看着他们的眼睛说,
this is what I know to be true in my life,
这就是我生命中真实的东西，
that there's a power inside of your body,
我体内有一种力量,
the ancient says the most powerful force in the universe.
古人说宇宙中最强大的力量。
The philosopher Neville early in the 20th century
20世纪早期的哲学家内维尔曾说过，
said that there's a power inside of every human
每个人内心都有一种力量，
against which no earthly force
任何世俗力量
is of the slightest consequence.
都无法与之抗衡。
I HAVE AN UNLIMITED POTENTIAL
我有无限的潜力
I did a whole bunch of research on cancer.
我做了一大堆关于癌症的研究。
I wanted to know who had beaten cancer and
我想知道谁战胜了癌症，
what was the common denominator.
他们的共同点是什么。
So I did a lot of reading and
我做了大量的阅读，
I discovered that the common denominator was everyone.
我发现了每个人身上的共同点。
No matter what treatment that they chose, they were well,
不管选择什么治疗方法，他们康复了，
because they changed the way they thought.
因为他们改变了其思维方式。
I knew that opening myself up physically
我知道，让外科医生来开刀，
to the surgeon's knife was an adjunct to true healing.
只不过是真正治愈的辅助手段。
And that I needed really to open spiritually.
真正需要的是打开灵性的大门。
Your body's not your enemy, which of course,
当然，身体不是你的敌人，
I think anyone who's first
我认为第一次
experience of disease or pain.
经历疾病或疼痛的人可能会这样认为。
I think we're taught that:
我认为，我们被教导过:
"Why is my body doing this to me instead of
“为什么我的身体这样对我，
why am I going through this experience?".
而不是为什么我要经历这种经历?”.
And it sort of let me shift my thinking to
这让我转变了我的想法，
I need to love my body through this.
即我需要通过这种方式来爱身体。
I'm thankful that I actually like cancer
我真的很感激我得了癌症，
because I needed a big wake up call.
因为我需要一个敲醒我的大警钟。
I was the type of person that needed almost
我是那种需要
to get hit between the eyes.
被狠狠敲击才会醒的人。
I'm in remission and I feel wonderful and
我的病情正在缓解，我感觉非常好，
I've never felt better about myself,
我从来没有感觉这么好过，
I still walk around daily.
我每天仍可以四处走动。
And I use that information that she had for cancer,
我利用她得到的癌症治疗信息,
"I love when we forgive and
就像 “我喜欢原谅和释放
release everything in my past",
我过去的一切”，
"I choose to fill my world with joy",
”我选择让我的世界充满欢乐”，
"I love and accept myself".
“我爱并接受自己”。
It was life changing.
这改变了我的一生。
It was one of these things where
这就是其中一个收获，
not only was I grateful for my illness but
我不仅对自己的疾病心存感激，
in the end much healthier than I had been before it.
而且最终我比以前健康得多。
MY HEALING IS ALREADY IN PROCESS
我的治疗已经开始了
There's an interesting thing that happens
当有人真的下载了一个
when somebody gets it really downloads
更积极的思考方式时，
a more positive way of thinking.
有趣的事情就会发生。
They get a hormonal balancing for one thing,
它们的荷尔蒙会因为一件事而平衡,
we know that when somebody is thinking with their heart,
我们知道当一个人用心思考时，
like they see a puppy or a sleeping baby,
就像他们看到一只小狗或者一个熟睡的婴儿,
your DHEA levels rise
其脱氢表雄酮水平上升，
which begins to balance your hormones.
这开始平衡你的荷尔蒙。
But something else really more important happens
但还有更重要的事情发生了，
and that is the beat to beat
那就是心脏的
variability of the heart normalizes.
搏动变化恢复正常。
And you get into this wave pattern that
而你进入这种波浪模式，
you can see on a heart rate monitor
你可以在心率监测器上看到
that actually begins to balance the entire body，
它实际上开始平衡整个身体,
given that the heart is a huge electromagnet
鉴于心脏是一个巨大的电磁铁，
that in fact trains the rest of the body.
事实上训练了身体的其他部分。
It's not a thinking process.
这不是一个思考的过程。
Thoughts are important.
思想是重要的。
The ancients made a distinction between
古人对思想、感受
thoughts and feelings and emotions.
和情绪有明确的区分。
And it's the feelings that are centered in our heart
正是我们内心深处的感受，
that there is an effect from that.
才会产生这样的效果。
That it changes the electrical and the magnetic field
它改变了我们心脏中的电场和磁场，
in our heart and that those fields literally change
而这些磁场确实改变了我们世界的构成，
the stuff that our world is made of, around their bodies.
改变了他们身体周围的物质。
And what the science now is showing
现在的科学研究表明，
is that when you can change the field that the atom is in,
当你能够改变那个原子所处的场,
you change the atom and we're made of those atoms.
你就改变了原子，而我们是由原子组成的。
So we have feelings in our hearts,
我们心里有感觉,
we're changing the field
我们正在改变
that connects the stuff everything is made of
连接万物所构成的场，
and we literally are altering our physical reality
我们实际上正在以听起来不可思议的方式
in ways that sound miraculous.
改变着我们周边的物理现实。
So this thought or the state of deep relaxation
所以这个想法或者深度放松的状态
or whatever it is,
或者其他什么的,
that enlightens you actually results in
会启迪你，实际上会导致
a decrease in stress hormones,
压力荷尔蒙的减少,
a normalization of blood sugar,
血糖恢复正常化,
decreasing of blood pressure
血压下降，
and a relaxation of all smooth muscles.
所有平滑肌松弛。
It is in fact a balance of the parasympathetic
它实际上是副交感神经和
and sympathetic nervous system.
交感神经的平衡。
Parasympathetic is the brake
副交感神经是刹车，
and sympathetic is the gas.
交感神经是油门。
And most people in this culture
在人们所处的文化中，
have the gas on all the time,
大多数人一直踩着油门，
with an occasional brake.
偶尔才会刹车。
So you're going around like this.
所以你就这样颠簸前行。
When both are in balance,
当两者达到平衡时，
you can work so much more efficiently
工作会更有效率，
and so much longer.
工作时间也可以更长。
Because you've got this beautiful Yin Yang balance.
因为你拥有了美妙的阴阳平衡。
The Sanskrit traditions have a seven energy center
梵语传统有一个七个能量中心
or seven chakras system that they work with.
或七个脉轮的系统，他们与之合作。
And they say the upper three or related
他们说，上三个或相关的脉轮，
what we call thought or logic processes.
是我们所谓的思想或逻辑过程。
So when we think about something,
当我们思考一些事情时,
we picture it in our mind,
我们在脑海中描绘它，
that perfect relationship or peace between nations.
比如国与国之间的完美关系或和平。
But we can only invite it into our lives
但只有当我们将情感的力量注入思想时，
when we breathe the power of emotion into that thought.
我们才能邀请它进入我们的生活。
The emotion comes from the lower three
而情感来自于我们身体的
or those creative centers in our bodies.
三个底部脉轮或者那些创造性中心。
So when we breathe
所以当我们通过思想
the power of emotion through our thought,
来呼吸情感的力量时，
we imbue that thought with life.
我们就给这个思想注入了生命。
And those two energies meet in the one center
这两个能量在一个中心相遇，
that is not accounted for yet in our model,
这个中心在我们的模型中还没有考虑到，
it's in our heart.
它就在我们的心里。
You look at these books by Beck,
你看看贝克的这些书,
all these fathers of cognitive-behavioral therapy.
所有这些认知行为疗法的创始人。
You open them up.
你打开这些书。
And the rewiring patterns that they give for
他们为强迫性人格障碍
obsessive compulsive personality disorder
或自私的自恋型人格
or selfishness of narcissistic personality or all these
或甚至有点混乱的正常人
or even just normal people who are a little messed up
所给出的重塑模式就是
was I love myself just the way I am.
我爱我自己如是。
So in my PHD and in my psychiatric residency
在我的博士学位和精神病学住院医生中，
and I'm now a neuropsychiatry
我现在是一个神经精神病学医生，
and I work in the field of intuition.
我的工作领域是直觉。
I've learned the biochemistry of how someone
我已经了解了人的生物化学，
we wires their thought patterns from
我们把他们的思维模式
I get one health problem after another two:
从我得到一个又一个的健康问题，变成了两个：
I love myself just the way I am, I am completely lovable.
我爱我自己如是，我是完全可爱的。
So I would be forever indebted to Louise Hay
我永远都会感激露易丝· 海
what she did to me personally
对我个人所做的一切，
because she woke me up.
因为她唤醒了我。
And literally what she has done as a revolutionary
而从字面上看，她所做的对我所学的课程，
for my perspective modern medicine.
即现代医学来说，是一场革命。
I seem to have been a born teacher.
我似乎是个天生的老师。
And I gathered a lot of people to me,
我召集了很多人，
I was doing workshops and classes.
我当时正在举办工作坊和培训课程。
And when the second book came out,
当第二本书出版时，
it was slow to start with.
刚开始时进展很慢。
And then the whole AIDS crisis struck.
然后整个艾滋病危机爆发了。
And for some reason, life said, you are going to be in it.
出于某种原因，生活告诉我，你将置身其中。
I didn't know anything about AIDS.
我对艾滋病一无所知。
Nobody knew anything about AIDS.
没有人知道艾滋病。
But I remember
但我记得
one day somebody called me up and said,
有一天有人打电话给我说，
"Louise, could you start a group for people with AIDS?".
“路易丝，你能为艾滋病患者成立一个团体吗?”。
And I said, "Well, I don't know, you know I don't know".
我说:：“我不知道艾滋病，你知道我对此一无所知。”
I said, "All right, let's meet".
我说，“好吧，让我们见个面吧”。
So we got together one night,
有天晚上，我们聚在一起，
there were six men in my living room.
客厅里有六个人。
We sat down and I said,
我们坐下来，我说,
"I don't know what we're going to do,
“我不知道我们该怎么办,
because nobody knows anything about this disease.
因为没人知道这种病。
But we're going to do what I've always done,
但我们要去做我已一直在做的事，
we're going to work on dissolving resentment,
我们要努力消除怨恨,
we're going to work on forgiveness,
我们要学会宽恕,
we're going to work on loving ourselves.
我们要学会爱自己。
And we are not going to play, ain't it awful.
我们不要只是在说，这是不是很可怕。
We are not gonna sit here and talk about how awful it is.
我们不能干坐在这里，谈论这有多糟糕”。
I said we're gonna take a positive approach.
我说，我们要采取积极的方法。
And anybody who learns anything
任何对这种疾病
positive about this disease,
有积极了解的人，
we're gonna come and share it.
我们会邀请他们并让其来分享。
If you have anything that's working for you,
如果你有什么对你有用的东西,
we're gonna share it and I talked about my ideas".
我们一起来分享，而且我也会聊聊我的想法。”。
And then we sang a song and
然后我们唱了一首歌，
did a little meditation at the end and they went home.
最后做了一些冥想，他们就回家了。
And the next day, one of the men called me and said,
第二天，其中一个人打电话给我说:
"Louise, it's the first time I've slept in three weeks".
“露易丝，这是我三个星期来，第一次睡了个好觉。”。
The next week, we had 25 people.
第二个星期，来了25个人。
And it started to grow and to grow and grow.
后来这个团体开始扩大，扩大，不断扩大。
And what it was, it was a safe place
那是一个安全的地方，
for people who were terrified out of their wits to come
让那些不知所措的人们来到这里，
and not be told they were bad,
不是被告知他们有多糟,
not be told there was something wrong with them,
不是被告知他们有什么问题,
but to take a positive approach.
而是采取积极的办法。
Within six months,
六个月内,
there were over 90 people in my living room
有超过90个人来到我的客厅，
and hanging out of the doors and windows
有着人徘徊在门窗外，
because there was no place to go.
因为没有空间可待了。
And then we got a gymnasium in west Hollywood.
后来我们在西好莱坞有了个体育馆。
And the next week it was 150 people.
第二周就来了150人。
And then the next thing you know
然后接下来的事情是，
we outgrew the gymnasium and
我们的人数超过了体育馆的容纳空间，
finally the city of Hollywood gave us a meeting home.
最后好莱坞市给了我们一个聚会场所。
We were having 850 people every week.
我们每周有850人。
People used to call each other up everything
人们过去常常打电话给对方，
going to the Hayride tonight?
说今晚去Hayride吗？
So we became known as the Hayride.
我们被称为Hayride。
I wanted to put this the Hayride on tape
我想把这些录下来
or make a movie of it or a video,
或者拍成电影或者录像，
so that it could go to other groups
这样它就可以送给其他团体，
and other groups could see what we were doing.
然后这些团体就可以了解我们在做什么。
I'd like you to continue to hold hands.
我希望你们继续手牵手。
Those of you are new and don't know our song,
你们有些人是新来的，还不知道我们的歌,
you'll learn it by next time.
下次你们就能学会了。
So I discovered then it would cost $40,000
我当时发现，在那个时候制作一个视频
to make a video at that time.
要花费4万美元。
And I thought, oh, my god, we don't have , two.
我感叹道，“哦，天哪，我们没有这么多钱，只有两万”。
But I kept knowing that we were going to make this video,
但我心里一直知道我们会拍这个视频，
it would be a good video,
这会是一个很好的视频，
it would go out and would go all these groups,
它会传播出去，分享所有这些群体，
those were my affirmations and I just kept saying them.
这是我的自我肯定，我会不停地说。
And then somebody came up to me and
后来有人来找我，他是个导演，
he was a director and he wanted to direct this thing.
他想导演这部电影。
And I said, wonderful.
我说，太好了。
And then the offshoot of that was,
然后这里面有个花絮，
that he said, all right,
他说，“好的
let me have, give me your foundation numbers.
请给我你的基金会号码”。
And I said, I don't have a foundation.
我说，“我没有基金会”。
And he said, okay,
他说，“好吧,
I'll have my account and set what up for you.
我会设立个帐户，并为你安排好一切。
And out of all that I got a foundation which I have today.
从这件事中，我有了一个基金会，我现在还拥有它。
And it's what I call give away money.
这就是我所说的捐出去。
Whatever money comes into that foundation
不管有多少钱进入该基金会，
is given away.
都会被捐出去。
But anyway we made this wonderful video
但是无论如何，我们制作了部很棒的视频，
called 'Doors Opening' ,
叫做《开门》 ，
about the group that we had at the time.
讲述了我们当时的小组。
This is the first time I've been to your group.
这是我第一次参加你们的小组。
Okay, welcome.
好的，欢迎。
Six weeks ago,
六周前,
I found out that I had
我发现我的四肢上
a malignant tumor in my limbs system.
长了一个恶性肿瘤。
Four weeks ago,
四周前,
I found out that it had spread substantially.
我发现它已经大范围地扩散了。
And two days ago I found out I had AIDS.
两天前我发现我得了艾滋病。
I need to hear a lot of what all of you are saying.
我需要听到你们所有人所说的很多话。
And there's a lot of people
在座的很多人
in this room that are friends of mine.
都是我的朋友。
I've been just real petrified to bring this out
我一直害怕把这件事说出来
and to talk about it.
并谈论它。
I've been having real symptoms.
我已经有了真正的症状。
I have doctors and T cell panels to back it up and even
医生和 T细胞板都验证了我的这个症状，
bone marrow biopsies to back it up and all this stuff.
甚至我还做了骨髓活检之类的监测，得到了同一结论。
And I've been trying to figure out what am I dying of.
我一直在试图弄明白我到底会怎么死。
Today I just want to find out what I'm living for
今天我只想知道我为什么而活，
and not what I'm dying of.
而不是我为什么而死。
When you talk, Tom, you talk for a lot of people,
汤姆，你说话的时候，代表了很多人,
you're not the only person.
你不是唯一的人。
And the thing is that,
问题是,
if you're looking for a savior,
如果你在寻找救世主，
and I know a lot of people here are looking for a savior,
我知道这里很多人都在寻找救世主，
the place to look is right here in the mirror.
不过救世主不在别处而就在镜子里。
Right here, honey.
就在这里，亲爱的。
This is the savior that you're looking for.
这就是你们要找的那个救世主。
What do you want to say to him?
你想对他说什么？
One of the things
如果可以的话，
that I would love to do in this world if I could
我在这个世界上最想做的一件事就是
was to see that everybody was fed
看到每个人都有饭吃、
and clothed and housed and loved
有衣穿、有房住、被爱着、
and had a fulfilling work and fulfilling creativity.
并有充实的工作和充实的创造力。
I think that would be wonderful.
我觉得那太好了。
But it's not that easy to do the whole world.
但是要让整个世界都做到并不那么容易。
However if I can do one individual at a time,
但是如果我可以一次帮助一个人，
when you have made your changes,
当你自己做出了改变，
you will automatically change people around you.
你就会自动改变你周围的人。
Because of the person that you are,
因为你是这样的人，
you will teach by example.
你要以身作则。
I don't heal anybody.
我不会治愈任何人。
That's not what I do, I just provide a space.
这不是我的工作，我只是提供一个空间。
Where we can uncover how absolutely wonderful we are.
在那里我们可以发现我们是多么的完美。
And many people find that
许多人发现
they are able to heal themselves.
他们能够疗愈自己。
And this is very heartwarming to all of us.
这对我们所有人来说都是非常感人的。
I was on the Phil Donahue show and the Oprah show.
我上过菲尔 · 多纳休的脱口秀和奥普拉的脱口秀。
And they both came out in the same week.
他们都在同一周上线。
And on that week,
就在那一周,
the Hay House went bananas, I mean,
Hay House像疯了一样，
the phones were ringing unbelievably.
电话响个不停。
And I won up my book 'You can heal your life'.
我的书《生命的重建》在众多书中胜出。
I won up on the bestseller list for 13 weeks.
连续13周蝉联畅销书排行榜。
And it's never been the same since.
从那以后，一切都不一样了。
Life just exploded this out.
人生就这样开挂了。
And the rest is history.
剩下的就是历史了。
Louise is the pioneer.
路易丝是先驱者。
She's the leader.
她是领导者。
She's the forerunner of what of
她是意识创造现实
the fact that consciousness creates reality,
这一事实的先驱，
consciousness is real,
意识是真实的，
consciousness is not some airy fairy baloney thing,
意识不是什么胡说八道的东西，
consciousness obeys the laws of physics.
意识遵循物理定律。
She said,
她说,
"Bless and prosper everyone around you,
“祝福和荣耀你身边的每一个人,
bless and prosper yourself".
而这也会祝福和荣耀你自己”。
And that's so deep,
那是如此深刻的领悟，
because when you love yourself, you love others.
因为当你爱自己的时候，你也会爱别人。
And what that is about is the fact that
这就是外部世界的一切
everything in the outside world is within us.
都在我们内心的事实。
And our molecules of emotion,
我们的情感分子,
they're not just within ourselves running our own body.
它们不仅仅在我们体内运行。
But they're a vibration, joining all of us.
它们也是一种振动，连接着我们所有人。
I'm willing to forgive.
我愿意宽恕。
Forgiveness of myself and others
宽恕自己和他人，
releases me from the past.
让我从过去中解脱出来。
Forgiveness is the answer to the most every problem.
宽恕是解决大多数问题的答案。
Forgiveness is a gift to myself.
宽恕是给我自己的礼物。
I forgive.
我宽恕。
And I set myself free.
从宽恕中我释放了自己。
The greatest accomplishment of my life
我人生最大的成就
was my ability to forgive my old father
就是我能够宽恕我老父亲，
who walked out on a whole family when we were just
在一个女人带着我们三个四岁不到的孩子时，
on a woman with three children under the age of four.
就离开了整个家庭。
I very often meditated and prayed to him
我经常冥想并为他祈祷，
then thank him for coming into the world
然后感谢他来到这个世界，
and teaching me the most important
教会我在这个星球上
lesson I had to learn on this planet,
必须学习的最重要的一课，
which was how to forgive.
那就是如何宽恕。
Mark Twain had a wonderful quote.
马克 · 吐温有一句精彩的名言。
He said,  "Forgiveness is the fragrance
他说： “紫罗兰把它的芬芳
that the violet sheds on the heel that has crushed it".
留在那踩扁了它的脚踝上，这就是宽恕”。
And I have an image of that.
我对此有一个印象。
What I call 'organic forgiveness'
我称之为‘有机宽恕’，
is a very great useful thing.
它是一个非常有用的理念。
And that is, when a person organically has
也就是说，当一个人声称对
an experience of forgiveness after
自己所有的感受负责之后，
claiming responsibility for all of their feelings.
就有机地体验到了宽恕。
So when I finally get in touch with,
当我终于遇到这类事情时，
oh, I feel hurt but that's inside me.
哦，我觉得很受伤，但那是我内心的感受。
It's not like you're doing it to me.
这与你对我做了什么无关。
That breeds organic forgiveness.
这会产生有机的宽恕。
When a person can claim responsibility
当一个人声称对自己
for things inside themselves,
内心的事情负起责任时，
that is a sign that they're in touch
这是它们触碰到
with their own vibration nature,
自身振动本质的迹象，
they're in touch with the forces of creation.
他们接触到了创造的力量。
Very good thing to do
当你感到不快乐的时候，
when you are feeling less than happy
你可以做的富有意义的事情，
is to look at it or whoever it is or whatever it is.
那就是看着它，不管那是谁，不管那是什么。
And take a notebook and write to the person's name
然后拿一个笔记本，写下这个人的名字
or the situation and say,
或者那个情况，然后说:
"What is it that I'm thinking about you
“我对你的看法到底是什么，
that I'm using as my excuse to not allow myself to be
我用它作为借口，不让自己成为
who I really am?".
真正的自己”
When you say,
当你说,
"What are you doing that's making me unhappy",
“你在做什么让我不开心”，
you're giving them all of the power,
你赋予他们所有的力量，
because they have to do something
因为他们必须做一些
different to make you happy.
别样的事情才能让你开心。
It's a very conditional love.
这是一种有条件的爱。
You're living a very conditional happiness.
你过着有条件的幸福生活。
Once you identify that and then think
一旦你认识到这一点，
the thought that who you really are would think.
然后想想，你真正是谁。
Now happiness is easy.
幸福其实很容易。
Coming into alignment is easy,
走向一致很容易，
it's just a matter of caring about
这只是一个关心你的感觉和
how you feel and practicing feeling good.
练习感觉良好的问题。
Whenever you have a conflict,
无论何时你有冲突，
any kind, in any relationship,
任何种类、任何关系的冲突，
whenever you have a conflict
无论何时当你有冲突时，
that the person who is willing to be
那个愿意成为道、
of TAO, of God, of source
上帝、源头的人
is the one who will practice forgiveness,
就是那个实践宽恕的人,
or will go to the person that they have a conflict with
或者会去找与他们有冲突的人，
and bring love to it.
并给他们带来爱的人。
Person who lives the life of a higher consciousness
过着更高意识生活的人，
is the person who says,
他们会说,
"I end all conflicts on love".
“我要用爱结束一切冲突”。
I forgive and I set myself free.
我宽恕并释放自己。
I forgive and I...
我宽恕并
HIDDEN TREASURE AT THE CENTER OF YOURSELF
隐藏在你内心深处的宝藏
In the early days when I work with people,
早些时候，当我和别人一起工作的时候，
I used to fix this problem and fix that problem
我习惯于修正这个问题，修正那个问题，
and you'd have this health thing
你有健康问题，
and we'd work on that and we'd work on this.
我们来解决那个问题，我们来解决这个问题。
And one day I discovered much to my amazement
有一天，我惊奇地发现，
that if I would help people learn to love
如果我能帮助人们学会爱自己，
themselves to really accept themselves as they are.
真正接受自己的本来面目。
We didn't have to work around problems
我们不需要解决问题，
because it was almost like a miracle,
因为这几乎是一个奇迹,
everything seemed to fall away,
一切似乎都消失了,
all the stuff that was in the way
所有挡路的东西，
and all the stuff that wasn't working.
所有不起作用的东西都消失不见了。
I've got this book by Louise Hay,
我有本露易丝· 海的书，
I start reading the book.
我开始读这本书。
And her whole emphasis was
她的整个重点
not underling with the disease so much,
并不是对疾病的过度关注,
but dealing with yourself
而是处理好你自己，
and dealing with do you love yourself.
处理好你是否爱你自己。
And I went through all the little exercises that she had,
我实践了她所有的小练习，
I'm doing the daily affirmations.
我在做每日肯定。
And what I realized that at 43 years old,
我意识到在我过往的43年中，
I had never learned how to love myself.
我从未学会如何爱自己。
I remember lots of times, I would ask people.
我记得很多次，我会问别人。
Well, what is really wrong with you,
你到底有什么毛病，
what have you done that is so terrible
你做了什么可怕的事，
that you're not acceptable to yourself?
以至于你自己都不能接受自己？
And I never ever ever got an answer
我从来没有得到过任何
that made any sense.
有意义的答案。
They might say something like, well, I'm too fat, so.
他们可能会说，我太胖了，所以，
I was very self-critical, you know,
我很会自我批评，
could think women go through this whole thing where,
会认为女人经历这一切,
it doesn't matter how other people tell you you look,
别人怎么说你的样子并不重要，
it matters how you feel you look.
重要的是你对自己的外表感觉如何。
When you look in the mirror and I used to
当你照镜子的时候，我经常看着镜子
look at myself in the mirror and I would see my flaws.
里的自己，我会看到自己的缺点。
I would see the things
我会看到
about myself that I wanted to change.
我想要改变的东西。
When you talk about loving yourself,
当你说爱自己的时候,
a lot of people think that's vanity.
很多人认为那是虚荣心作祟。
But it isn't really, it has nothing to do with that.
但事实并非如此，与此毫无关系。
If you look in the mirror,
如果你照照镜子,
just simple things,
只是些简单的事情,
like looking in the mirror in your own eyes and say,
就像看着镜子里的自己说,
"I love you, I really really love you".
“我爱你，我真的很爱你”。
And it helps if you use your name,
如果你用自己的名字,
"Louise, I love you, I really love you".
“露易丝，我爱你，我真的爱你”。
It gets to that little child inside.
它会影响到里面的小孩子。
That has been rejected for so long.
这已经被拒绝了很长时间。
And it breaks open sort of a dam or
它打开了一个水坝或者一
a door whatever you want to call it.
扇门，随便你怎么叫它。
And it's like little miracle start to happen,
就像奇迹开始发生,
lots of little good things happen.
有很多好事发生。
In all the work that I did with what she taught me,
在我用她教我的方法做的所有工作中,
within three months the cancer was gone.
三个月之内，癌症就消失了。
I am clear now and I feel fabulous.
我现在清醒了，感觉棒极了。
You can recognize that
你可以认识到你
you are a being that has self-worth.
是一个有自我价值的存在。
Then you start to treat yourself differently.
然后你开始以不同的方式对待自己。
And I think that's what so very
我认为爱自己
important about loving yourself is
最重要的就是不
you stop beating yourself up,
要再自责,
you stop making yourself wrong,
你不再犯错,
you stop talking about how awful you are.
你不要再说你有多糟糕了。
And you start to treat yourself
你开始对自己有一
with a certain amount of respect.
定程度的尊重。
And this makes an enormous difference because
这会产生巨大的不同，因为
what you give out in life is what comes back to you.
你在生活中付出的东西会回到你身边。
The fastest journey to loving oneself
爱自己最快的旅程就是
is to look for things to appreciate everywhere you look.
到处寻找可以欣赏的东西。
Because if you can find something
因为如果你能在那朵
to appreciate in that flower,
花里找到可以欣赏的东西,
you're not in that moment,
你不在那个时刻,
a vibration discord to loving yourself.
一个不和谐的振动到爱你自己。
If you can find appreciation in that child's face
如果你能从孩子的脸上或朋友的美
or in the beauty of a friend,
貌中找到欣赏,
as you find things to appreciate,
当你发现值得欣赏的东西时,
the vibration of appreciation
感激的振动
and the vibration of love are identical vibrations.
和爱的振动是相同的振动。
I love and accept myself.
我爱并接受自己。
Deep in the center of me
在我的内心深处
flows an infinite wells of love.
流淌着无限的爱之井。
Love fills my whole being,
爱充满了我的整个生命,
and radiates out for me in all directions,
从四面八方向我散发出来,
returning to me multiplied.
回到我身边的人越来越多。
I give and receive more love every day.
我每天给予和接受更多的爱。
And the supply is endless.
而且供应是无限的。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I take loving care of my body.
所以我爱护我的身体。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I provide for myself a comfortable home.
因此我为自己提供了一个舒适的家。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I work at a job that I truly enjoyed doing.
因此，我的工作是我真正喜欢做的。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I behave and think
因此，我对所有人的行为
in a loving way to all people.
和思想都是充满爱的。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I forgive and totally release the past.
因此我原谅并完全释放过去。
I love myself,
我爱我自己,
therefore I live in the now,
所以我活在当下,
experiencing each moment as good.
体验每一个美好的时刻。
And knowing that my future is bright
我知道我的未来是光明的，
and joyous and secure,
快乐的，安全的,
for I am a beloved child of the universe.
因为我是宇宙中受人爱戴的孩子。
And the universe lovingly takes care of me,
宇宙慈爱地照顾着我,
now and forevermore.
从现在到永远。
I love you.
今夜月色很美。
I really love you.
我真的很爱你。
The path of change is a lifelong process.
改变的道路是一个终生的过程。
As you go farther along the path,
当你沿着这条路走得更远的时候,
you began to see one miracle after another.
你开始看到一个又一个奇迹。
Learning to stay open and accept those miracles
学会保持开放并接受这些奇
is one of the most important stages of your growth.
迹是你成长最重要的阶段之一。
No gardener is ever going to go out into a garden
没有园丁会走到花园里说，
and say, "Give me some vegetables
“给我一些蔬菜，然后我可能
and then maybe I'll water you".
会给你浇水”。
It that's not the way manifestation occurs.
这不是显化发生的方式。
What you do is you go out
你要做的就
and you tend to the vegetables and you water them
是出去照料蔬菜，
and then the harvest comes.
浇水，然后收获就来了。
So if you're giving out a feeling of I'm okay,
所以如果你觉得我没事,
I'm good enough as I am and I am acceptable
我足够好，我是可以接受的，
and I love life and I love me.
我热爱生活，我爱我自己。
And you start having gratitude for yourself and for life
你开始对自己和生活感恩
then life treats you differently because
那么生活对你的态度就不同了
you are having a different vibration
你感觉到了不同的震动
that you're giving out and getting back.
你给出去，然后回来。
And that's when things really start to flow.
这就是事情真正开始流动的时候。
What was interesting the challenge for me was
有趣的是，对我来说，
that I thought there was limits
这个挑战是我认为你能走
to how far you could take this.
多远是有限度的。
And I have to credit Louise Hay as the person
我不得不相信露易丝 · 海是让我开
who opened my eyes that it's unlimited.
阔眼界的人，她让我认识到这是无限的。
She did it on her own, a woman,
她自己做的，一个女人,
publisher, who has changed millions of lives worldwide.
他改变了全世界数百万人的生活。
Her house overlooking the ocean and her organic garden
她的房子可以俯瞰大海，她的有机花
and her beautiful koi pond.
园和她美丽的锦鲤池塘。
To me were just physical representations of heaven
对我来说，这只是她用自己的思想创造
on earth that she'd made with her own thoughts.
出来的天堂在人间的物理表现。
No one inspired someone by being sick or broke or poor.
没有人会因为生病、破产或贫穷而激励别人。
If you want to help someone, you let it shine.
如果你想帮助别人，就让他们发光发亮。
You become that beacon on the hill.
你变成了山上的灯塔。
The universe loves grateful people.
宇宙喜欢感恩的人。
The more grateful you are, the more you get.
你越感激，你得到的就越多。
To be grateful about,
为了感恩,
it's that simple.
就这么简单。
Life is really very simple.
生活其实很简单。
We make it enormously complicated.
我们让事情变得非常复杂。
But it doesn't have to be.
但事实并非如此。
We all go through an evolutionary process in our growth
在我们的成长过程中，我们都会经历一个进化的过程，
where we start out wishing and hoping
在这个过程中，我们开始希望、希
and believing that the universe is like Santa Claus.
望和相信宇宙就像圣诞老人一样。
And all you have to do is write your list up
你所要做的就是写下你的清单，然后
and you get what you want.
你就能得到你想要的。
But there's a commitment to consciousness
但是有一种对意识的承诺和
and a commitment to action,
对行动的承诺,
that's necessary in order to be able
这是必要的，以便能够显
to manifest the things that we affirm or we intend.
示的事情，我们肯定或我们打算。
When I was wish washy about wanting to soulmate,
当我希望找到灵魂伴侣的时候,
I got wish washy results.
我得到了希望渺茫的结果。
I got this guy writes poetry
我让一个家伙写诗这
and this guy has a good job,
个家伙有份好工作,
so put him together,
所以把他放在一起,
I got a summit.
我有个峰会。
But when I got clear,
但当我清醒过来后,
right away it happened.
马上就发生了。
Nobody in the history of my family that I know of
据我所知，在我们家族的历史上，从来
has ever had a successful relationship.
没有人有过成功的恋爱关系。
I realized that it would be breaking
我意识到这将开
absolutely radical new ground,
辟绝对激进的新领域,
if I was able to create a relationship that worked,
如果我能创造一段有效的关系,
that that would be an unthinkable thing to do.
那是不可想象的事情。
And what better thing to make happen
还有什么比完全不可想象的事
than something completely unthinkable.
情更好的事情发生呢。
And so I designed what I wanted
所以我在脑海中设计了我想
in a close relationship in my mind.
要的亲密关系。
And honesty a relationship where
诚实是一种我们都可以自由追
both of us were free to pursue our creativity,
求创造力的关系,
our creative callings.
我们的创造性使命。
And that each of us took
我们每个人都要对自己
full responsibility for our lives.
的生活负起全部责任。
So that we didn't get into blaming each other.
这样我们就不会互相指责了。
From that moment,
从那一刻起,
it only took a month until Katie came into my life.
只过了一个月，凯蒂就走进了我的生活。
And basically set the tone for our .. last 27 years together.
基本上为我们在一起的27年定下了基调。
I have an intention that says,
我的意图是,
I want to meet a partner that I love,
我想遇见一个我爱的人,
I want to have a relationship that's meaningful to me.
我想拥有一段对我有意义的感情。
But then the next question I ask myself is
但接下来我问自己的问题是：
how do I need to grow and evolve
我需要怎样成长和
in order to become that partner.
进化才能成为那个伴侣。
So that I can attract that partner to me.
这样我才能吸引那个伙伴。
All my relationships are harmonious.
我所有的人际关系都很和谐。
And deeply fulfilled by all that I do.
我所做的一切都让我深感满足。
Every experience is a success.
每一次经历都是成功的。
I deserve the best and I accept it now.
我应该得到最好的，现在我接受了。
And listen with love to invite his messages.
带着爱倾听，邀请他的留言。
I am healthy, whole and complete.
我是健康的，完整的，完整的。
I express gratitude for all the good in my life.
我对我生命中所有的美好表示感谢。
Each day brings wonderful new surprises.
每一天都会带来新的惊喜。
Everything that everyone wants,
每个人都想要的一切,
whether it is a material object,
无论它是一个实物,
a state of being, a relationship,
一种存在的状态，一种关系,
a pile of money, a circumstance and event,
一大笔钱，一个环境和一件事,
every single thing without exception,
无一例外,
that you have ever wanted or ever will want is because
是因为你认为拥有它
you think you will feel better in the having of it.
会让你感觉更好。
So if you will let your primary intention be to feel good,
所以如果你想让自己感觉良好,
you will work all of the wrinkles out of this
你要把你所经历的这段旅程
evolving journey that you're upon.
中所有的皱纹都消除。
This is how it's worked for me.
我就是这么做的。
Every time I've visualized and referred,
每次我想象和引用,
I get this inner road map given to me in the form of
我得到了这张内心路线图，它以直觉的形式呈现
gut feelings that are repetitive
在我面前，这种直觉反复地
that urge me to take action or visions.
促使我采取行动或者产生愿景。
I was married to a man who
我嫁给了一个决定通过
decided to control me by telling me how awful I was.
告诉我我有多糟糕来控制我的男人。
And I believed him for a long time
我相信了他很长一段时间，
and my self-esteem just plummeted.
我的自尊心一落千丈。
I didn't think that I could do anything in the world
除了做一个好母亲，我认为这是
except for being a wonderful mother to my sioux sons
一个重要的目标，我不认为我
which I think is an important purpose.
能做世界上任何事情。
But there was something more,
但还有更多的东西,
I would pray all the time, tell me my life purpose.
我会一直祈祷，告诉我我的人生目标。
I kept getting these visions to go give speeches
我一直幻想着去演讲，但我不
and I didn't know how to do it.
知道该怎么做。
Because what could I this person,
因为我怎么可能这个人,
we didn't have any confidence possibly teach anyone.
我们没有任何自信可以教任何人。
What I later learned is that we don't have to worry about
我后来学到的是，我们不
how to put our visions or
必担心如何把我们的幻
dreams into reality.
想或梦想变成现实。
All we have to do is follow the guidance
我们所要做的就是遵循指导，
that we get one step at a time.
一步一个脚印。
It's very common for us
我们通常会通过
to overwhelm ourselves to frighten ourselves by
思考最终结果来压倒自己，
thinking about the end result,
以此来恐吓自己,
it's so big.
太大了。
Here I am as somebody who wants to write a book,
在这里我是一个想写书的人,
oh, my god, how am I gonna write a best seller.
天啊，我怎么能写出一本畅销书。
There are things you need to learn between A and Z
在 A 和 Z 之间，有些事情你需要学习，
that you can't complete Z until you learn them.
但是在你学会它们之前，你是不能完成 Z 的。
Overcoming self-doubt, for example,
例如，克服自我怀疑,
is one of those things.
就是其中之一。
And so that's why you take step B,
这就是为什么你要采取步骤B，
because maybe you just have a little
因为也许你只是
bit of self-doubt about going
有一点点自我怀疑，
to the book store to buy that book
去书店买那本关于
on writing a book proposal.
写建议书的书。
It's not enough just to ask,
光问是不够的,
it's not enough just to have positive thoughts,
仅仅有积极的想法是不够的,
you've got to follow the guidance you get as a result.
你必须遵循你得到的指导。
Sometimes people tell me that they feel
有时人们告诉我，他们
like their prayers are being ignored.
觉得自己的祈祷被忽视了。
Because the universe gives us
因为宇宙给了我们小小的
little baby steps one step at a time.
一步一步来的步骤。
It's often unrecognized
当你被要求去读一本书
when you're told to go read a book,
的时候，你通常不会意识到,
take a class, call someone, write a letter.
上课，打电话，写信。
But if we do step A,
但是如果我们做了第一步,
then we're given the next set of instruction step B,
然后是下一步指令 b,
then we're given the next set of instruction step C.
然后我们会得到下一组指令 c。
And it takes a step by step to where we're going.
这需要我们一步一步地走下去。
As your desire is moving
当你的欲望在移动，你在
and you are moving in the direction of it,
朝着它的方向移动,
you feel the ease of that.
你能感觉到那种轻松。
It's only when you turn in opposition
只有当你反对时，你才会
that you feel the resistance of all that.
感受到所有这些的阻力。
I began in my bedroom literally in Santa Monica
我从圣塔莫尼卡的卧室开始的，
with my 90 year old almost blind and almost deaf mother
当时和我一起生活的是我90岁的
who lived with me at that time.
几乎失明和失聪的母亲。
She would help me mail the books and things like that.
她会帮我邮寄书籍之类的东西。
It was a very very small operation
这是一个非常非常小的行动，
we were just doing what we could.
我们只是尽我们所能。
And we're now in 35 different languages and 30 countries.
我们的书已被翻译成35种不同的语言，并在30个国家出版。
It's very interesting to me
对我来说很有趣的是
that ever since I put my foot on the spiritual pathway,
自从我踏上了灵性之路,
it is as though I've had nothing to do with my life.
就好像我和我的生活一点关系都没有了。
Life has taken over and said you will do this,
生活接管了一切，说你要做这个,
you will go here, this will happen,
你将去这里，
this will happen, this will happen.
这会发生，这那发生。
I just do what's in front of me,
我从一开始
from the very beginning.
只做眼前之事。
We answered the telephone,
我们接了电话,
we opened the mail and did what was in front of us.
打开信件，做好眼前的事情。
And things kept growing and growing and growing.
事物不断地发展，发展，发展。
My vision was how can I help the people,
我的愿景是如何帮助人们,
how can I help people.
我怎样才能帮助别人。
This is my life.
这是我的人生。
This is really my life.
这就是我的人生。
To me, I think enlightenment is
对我来说，我认为开悟是
letting go of all the things we believe
放下我们所相信的所有
that are not benefiting us in life
对我们的人生没有好处的东西，
or that barriers to our life to the good things in life.
或对我们的生活有障碍之物，以获得生活中的美好事物。
And to release them one by one,
一个接一个地释放它们，
and just think I don't have to believe that anymore
想着我不必再相信这些，
or do I want to believe that anymore
或者想我是否要再相信，
and making a conscious choice.
并做出有意识的选择。
It feels like what surrender feels like
当你如此执着于一个结果而
when you've been so attached to an outcome
最终放手时，感觉就像
and you finally let go.
臣服的感觉。
And you feel this deep sense of relief
当你知道牌会倒下，
in knowing that what the cards are
它们会倒下时，
gonna fall the way, they're gonna fall.
你会感到深深的解脱感。
And I have the ability to handle whatever happens.
无论发生什么，我都有能力处理。
It feels like awe.
这种感觉就像是敬畏。
There's just this powerful knowing
知道自己并不孤单是一种
that you're not alone.
强大的力量。
So we can give it a lot of different names,
所以我们可以给它起很多不同的名字,
but the key is that we are I believe much
但关键是我相信我们比过去被
greater than we've been led to believe in the past.
引导相信的要伟大得多。
And I think that's where the healing really begins unless
我认为这才是疗愈的真正开始，
understanding and accepting that power in our lives.
除非理解并接受我们生活中的这种力量。
You cannot fake your point of attraction, can you?
你不能伪装你的吸引点，是吗？
It is what it is.
事实就是如此。
And everything in the universe is reflecting it back to you.
宇宙中的一切都会反射回你身上。
I have great gifts.
我有很好的天赋。
I have an incredible life.
我有着不可思议的生活。
But I've had a few problems.
但是我遇到了一些问题。
I have a little bit of a back problem.
我的背有点问题。
I fall asleep in a weird way.
我入睡很奇怪。
But I have been given incredible opportunities.
但是我得到了难以置信的机会。
It all began was reaching up for that book,
这一切都是从拿起那本书开始的,
with Louise Hay's "You can heal your life".
露易丝· 海的《你可以治愈你的生命》。
I follow my inner ding what I call my inner ding.
我追随内心之声，我称之为内心叮当。
Yes, well, it's that feeling you're instinct.
是的，就是你是直觉的那种感觉。
It's an instinct thing and
这是一种直觉的东西，
it either feels right or it doesn't?
让你感觉到合适与否？
I follow my inner ding.
我追随内心的叮当声。
Excuse me.
不好意思。
Which path goes down to the beach?
哪条路通向海滩？
Yeah, you have to turn around and go...
是的，你得转过身，然后去...
Dude, I'm actually going down there.
伙计，我也要去那里。
You want me to show you.
你来给你指路。
I am who I am, I fell like I'm never gonna be good enough.
我就是我，我觉得我永远都不够好。
I'm willing to change.
我愿意改变。
What you think?
你觉得怎么样？
And what you believe is what will come true for you.
你所相信的就是你将要实现的。
Your thoughts create your life.
你的思想创造了你的生活。
It's that simple.
就是这么简单。
And when we can get that,
如果我们能做到,
we can make enormous changes.
我们可以做出巨大的改变。